Heat. Heat. [music]
[bell]
[bell and music]
[bell] Heat. Heat.
[music]
[bell]
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat.
Heat.
Hello, good evening, good day everybody
and welcome back to the Ask Show. I hope
you're all doing great. This is episode
327 and I'm going to take questions from
the super chat today as many as I can uh
over the next couple of hours or so.
Before we do that, let's see who is
there on the live chat. Arun Romesh,
Baskcar Bandit, Sharon B3M,
uh, Sharon B3M, Baskar Bandit. Who else
do we have? Anikit, Anikit is there. Who
else? DN0 HR is here. Uh, Manhattan I6W
Geopolitical Dubai is always here from
Indor. Good to see you. Always sir, good
to see you. Thank you so much. Honey
Sharma, uh, Honey Sharma is here. Vidy
Manar, good evening ma'am. Honey Kit
once again. SKR7733.
Madav Gupta 38. Um Adwit Ashwini Ngui
Manhattan Raika Huml Jes Ma'am Madav
Gupta 38 Shri Sudir Kumar Jes Madav
Gupta Anu
um geopolitical once again real painter
real painter Nirvana Shanks
Nirvana Shanks son MK Madav Gupta uh
Nabit Tadas Namaste Anime Paratia Ram s
online.
Uh uh who else we have? Feel strong man.
Good to see you sir. Um Field Strong Man
Honey Bagger Honey Badger of Kalinga.
That's quite a name. Chhattabish.
Chhattabish. Good to be back. Good to
see you sir. Good to see you once again.
Jasan Singh. Good morning. Sumit Agarwal
Mojour Partam Sharma Manhattan. Anime
Baratia, Abishek Shastav, Abishek Shukla
live, um Anu
Ashikade,
History Go, uh anonymous scientist, Bon
Bonjour, good to see you. Oh, it's good
to see you sir.
Tak Raguir Soleni Madav Gupta feel
strong manpin
aband from U Jnatar Namaste G real
painter once again long time good to see
you G Manish namaste ma'am as always
Swami hi uh who else um Swami is here
from Jaipur the Arian Raj is here
Gajapati Dv from Odisha good good
evening sir Abhisha live from Kpur
Um,
Raguir Soleni is a visual student.
Sumitagarwal Hola Tech G78807.
Namaste. Asal 24. General Sumutai is
here with us. Somi says, "Have I seen
the thing?" Quite a movie. I've seen it.
Yes. Science fiction, horror of some
sort. Yes, good movie. Vijay Vagela,
good to see you, sir. Um, who else? Who
else? Who else? Everybody else. Vidit
Chhat where is it? Vidit Chhatrellia.
Okay. Uh SKR7733
is here from Takashila India. Well, good
to see you sir from Takashila India. Uh
CVS 2K6 from Andhra Pradesh. Namaskaram
G. Sujit Sha Gunda good to see you. Uh
General Subutai is here from Mongolia of
course. Yes. Uh Anurag Dikshit. Mar Kane
good to see you ma'am. Good morning.
Vihang Kuran from Mumbai and everybody
else. Okay. So let us Apurva Apurva.
Yes. Uh dragons one to three slayer is
also here. Abishakas says dharma will
rise a dharma will lose. One certainly
hope so and we should work for work work
towards that.
Okay. Um
Tutti Patel. Namaste. Namaste. Hello.
Tech G7. Namaste. and anonymous
scientist is here from Lucknau. Okay. Uh
enough of greetings. Let us get going
with the questions. What do we have
today? Arun Romesh. Thank you very much
sir. Thank you very much indeed. Uh
Basar Bandit says Piety. Piety sir
Baskar G. Um hope I'm well. Yes, I'm
well. Thank you. I hope you are well as
well. Uh very ghastly disturbing info
coming out from the Epstein files. Yuck.
Some entity allegedly trying to arm
twist the US to strike Iran anytime now.
Also, it seems Trump won't win the
midterms. Well, the the the Epstein
files uh revelations that are coming out
are utterly ghastly, disgusting,
disturbing, concerning. I mean, inhuman,
monstrous. I don't have the words to
describe what we are seeing. I mean,
every conspiracy theory is coming is
turning out to be true.
Everything that was that was described
as conspiracy theories, all of that is
come is has turned out to be true. The
Pizzagate stuff, I mean, the the
Satanism, the the the all the stuff. I
mean, it's horrific. Howard Lutchnik,
what a depraved, disgusting person. And
what about his boss, Donald J. Trump?
Where is he today? He's not on X. He's
not on Truth Social. Truth Social.
I mean Nikki Haley
h I mean what do I say about these
people
monsters.
The people who are ruling that country
the United States are monsters
right and they go this nation goes
around preaching human rights and
democracy to the world.
I mean, what can I say? Terrible. Uh,
the question Baskar Bandit is asking is
that is there some entity that's
allegedly trying to arm twist the US to
strike Iran anytime now? Well, that's
what some people are speculating. Some
people are speculating. Let me just say
it straight. Some people are speculating
that this uh see the question is how
come Donald J. Trump's government has
released these files which
prove that this guy is a pedophile and a
pervert and god knows what else. Donald
J. Trump, how come his government has
released stuff that is so essentially
incriminating about him, about the
president?
Does he have no control over his
government?
Does somebody else control the
government of the U FBI and whatn not?
Who could that somebody else be? So some
people are speculating that the United
States is controlled by Israel. Okay,
that's speculation by some people. The
US is controlled by Israel and the FBI
is controlled by Israel and everything
is controlled by the is by the Israelis
and the Israelis want Trump to strike at
Iridan and he has not done this so far.
That's why they're pressurizing him by
releasing some part of the Epstein
files. Maybe there's more about Trump.
Who knows? So that's the speculation
that some people are indulging in. Um
what do I think? I have no idea. I could
not possibly say whether it's true or
not.
Uh so I don't know.
Yeah. If if if hypothetically
theoretically Israel does control the
United States and Trump is dragging his
feet about is about striking Iran, then
well from a logical perspective kind of
makes sense. But does Israel really
control the US like some people say? I
don't know about that. Um it seems that
Trump won mid will not win the midterm
elections. That's November this year,
right? That's still a way away. Uh in
the US, you know what? Who knows? He may
even win the midterms. The I don't know.
The people of the US seem to be fine
with this the sort of stuff. I have no
idea. But yeah, it looks likely that he
will lose the midterms. We we'll see
about that. It will make him a weaker
president than what he is right now.
Unless he does some fantastic things, in
which case everything is forgiven.
So we'll see about that. Bascar Bandit
says uh Baloi's tore through 12 cities
yesterday. Some reports are even saying
that u core commander Pakistani army in
Kuwa has left. Um how is the Balojasthan
angle connected to Iran US instability
right now. Um look the US
uh is pro Pakistan. The US wants it
needs Pakistan to be the strong stable
nation reasonably stable at least. so
that it counterbalances offsets India.
So the so Pakistan is important for the
US and if something goes wrong in
Balojasthan like what we see right now
it's not good for Pakistan which means
it's not good for for American
interests. The Americans need a stable
Pakistan not just to counterbalance
India but also to potentially do
something in Iran whenever the time they
decide is right. So if they want to
let's say not go ahead with a full
strike on Iran but destabilize Iran
gradually through terrorism the
Americans do that right they've used
Pakistan against India like this in the
past for decades so the Americans in
that case would need Pakistani
terrorists to enter Iran from the east
right but if Balojasthan is no longer in
Pakistan's full control then that
doesn't work that doesn't happen
so I would say this is not working out
well for the US if Balojasthan is
unstable if Baloi rebel are succeeding
in taking over cities and maybe even
Quita POS possibly, right? Um so I would
not say that the US is behind this. So
who else could be behind it? Well, I
don't I could not possibly speculate. Um
um yeah. So I I don't know how the US
could be behind this. Obviously
Baloistan, if you look at the map, okay,
let's open the map. All right. Um let's
put the map on the screen and let's look
at Baluchistan. It it clearly is a
border border region between the
temporary nation and Iran as well as
Afghanistan. So let's look for
Baluchistan.
Okay.
Baluchistan Pakistan temporarily part of
Pakistan. So once again it doesn't give
you the outline but yeah. So Bulajjustan
is this western part of Pakistan. And
some of it is it borders Afghanistan,
queta as you can see over here and Iran
as well.
So if Baljasthan is unstable, the
Americans can't really use Pakistan to
push terrorists into Iran which could be
a problem for the Americans. So um I
doubt the Americans would be behind
this. Why would they destabilize their
own asset? Doesn't make sense.
So yeah, we'll see how it goes.
Okay. Aniket says how Indian and English
days are the same like Raviar Sunday.
Well,
it's even that way in French.
Okay. So, Ravivar
is deos in French. Dimosh, I don't know
what's the origin, but uh savvar
Monday is learni. Lundi comes from lun
which means the moon. Monday is ladi is
is somir. Monday is moon day. Somar s is
also moon. It's not just English. It's
also French. Okay. Tuesday is Thursday.
Tyr is this Nordic deity. Uh that is uh
the counterpart of the Roman god Mars
which is also mongal. Mongalwar Tuesday
and uh mi in French. Once again, Mars.
Uh, what's what's Wednesday? Wednesday
is vooden or
>> [clears throat]
>> udin, right? That's bud bud.
That's Mercury me in French. And so it
can you can go through the all the days
of the week. They all are the same. They
have the same meaning whether it is
Sanskrit, whether it's Hindi, whether it
is English, whether it's French. I
suppose other European languages as
well. which shows that there is some
ancient common tradition that under that
that is the foundation of all these all
the names of the days in various
Indo-Uropean languages
right that's what it tells us and says
baseball or cricket which one is hard
interesting complex well I don't really
I'm not really familiar with the rules
of baseball
um baseball I think has multiple innings
and uh a six is a home run and that sort
of thing and this this you know you can
only play in this this particular angle
that sort of thing cricket it's like
360° I think overall it looks like
cricket is more complex
uh interesting well if you're American
cricket is boring for you if you're
Indian uh baseball I'm sure is boring so
that's a subjective question for me I
don't really know the rules of baseball
so I can't say whether I would find
baseball interesting or
As far as cricket is concerned, it's
pretty complex for sure.
Okay. Sharon says, "How can be Indian?
His ancestors were from Iran and settled
here." Many Indian Shia Muslims fu
fu
fouad mira
also trace trace their roots to Iran
19th century. So how can Rhulah Kamei be
Indian is the question that Sharon is
asking and it's a valid question of
course it's a legitimate question. So
let's look at first of all who was
Rhulah Khabi. Let's take a look at the
gentleman's face
ruli.
So the former supreme leader of Iran of
Iran Iran Persia this is okay. Um and if
you if you see his nickname that he he
used for himself, it was Hindi. Okay.
This is in Hindi obviously. No, no, no,
no, no. Al Hindi, was it Al Hindi? He
called himself al- Hindi or something.
Um he the suffix Hindi meaning from
India was used by his grandfather and
sometimes by Rahul Kami himself in his
poetry. Uh so he used to write gazals.
Okay.
And uh in some of his gazels he uses the
the nickname Hindi for himself. So
what's the deal? His grandfather was was
from his father's name was Syad Ahmed
Musavi Hindi. Okay. He was born in Kinur
in Uttar Pradesh in the 1800s. And his
parents I mean his father at least he he
they his his ancestors they migrated to
India from Iran in the 18th century. Now
Rola Kamehameh's grandfather was born in
in India but then he at a certain age he
left India and he went to Iraq and then
to Iran and then he settled down in the
in the town of Hain in Iran and that's
how the name Kamei uh comes about.
So that's the story. Now his grandfather
was born in India for sure we know that
who he he called himself sayyad ahmed
musabi hindi. So he was born in India
but obviously that doesn't necessarily
make you Indian if your ancestors were
Persian. Did his father have an Indian
mother? We don't know for sure. His
father definitely did not did not marry
Indian women. His father I think married
three women whatever it is sorry
grandfather. So we don't know for sure
but he called himself Hindi
and even Kamei Rohul Kamei called
himself Hindi at times. So that's the
Hindi or Indian origin.
uh genetically I'm not sure how much
Indianness is then is there in Nurola
Kmeni or his grandfather I'm not sure of
that but uh they called themselves Hindi
his grandfather called himself Hindi and
Kmeni himself called himself Hindi
that's why one can say that he had a
Indian grandfather now you make of it
whatever you want if you don't like them
to be called hind Indian or Hindi that's
your choice all right okay basar bandit
says how bat to make how bat to make use
of its rare earth reserve by preserving
nature. Given how environmental
environment damaging rare earth mining
is some suggest in north Burma where
Chinese China mines them a lot of cancer
happens. Look mining [snorts] is going
to be damaging. Mining is going to be
terrible. Mining means you tear up the
earth, dig it up, extract you know or
which is earth with a little bit of
whatever substance you're looking for.
Then you process it through chemical
processes and other processes which are
pretty damaging to the environment. And
that's how you extract what you're
looking for. And it's not just rare
earth mining that's damaging to the
environment. It's essentially all mining
that's damaging to the environment.
Okay. Uh now the US, it also has rare
earths on its territory. I'm not sure
how many how much of the world's
reserves the US has, but the US also has
it. But the US doesn't mind it. The US
pres prefers to have other countries do
that the mining and the and the
purification process because it's
environmentally damaging. The US wants
North America to be as clean and
beautiful and pretty and as undamaged as
possible. That's why the Americans they
export their garbage, their trash to
third world countries for for it to be
recycled or or done whatever the the
these countries want. The Americans
don't want all this trash in America.
That's why they export it to other
countries. Now India has probably the
world's largest rare earth reserves.
Okay. But we haven't done a thing about
it and that's why we are completely
dependent on China right now. So let's
say we go ahead and we want to
operationalize
the rare earth reserves. We want to
start mining them and not just mining.
We whatever ore we extract we want to
process it and we want to be the end to
end you know consumer of the thing. We
ex we we extract we mine and extract it.
We process it and we use the the end
product and maybe we even export it
because we are the largest um you know
nation with reserves.
So in that case we're going to have to
uh do mining and processing. Now you are
right if you look at northern Burma I've
shown it in the past on on Google on the
on the maps. You have all these rare
earth mines in northern Burma, right?
Right west of the Chinese border with
northern Burma. And all of that mining
and extracting and and processing is
done and then it's shipped off to China.
Okay. And these rare earth reserves in
northern Burma are one of the reasons
for the civil war in Burma, which is a
proxy war between the Chinese and the
Americans. Um, and yeah, if you if you
do all this processing, this this
damaging processing, you know, with with
chemicals and whatnot, you're going to
have effects, side effects of that, I
suppose, you know, uh, you're going to
have more cancer like you're saying. I
mean, it's it's weird because in the far
east of India, states like Manipur, the
incidence of cancer is much higher. It
seems to be quite high. Uh, so this is
going to be an issue. So how can India
make use of its reserves while
preserving nature? Well, you try to
preserve nature as far as possible. Uh
wherever the rare earth deposits are,
you do the mining. Um and you make sure
that the processing is done as cleanly
as possible. But beyond a point, you
can't do a thing about it. Beyond a
point, there's going to be some damage
to the environment. And that's just the
way it is. That is something you either
accept or you simply don't mind the
stuff. That's it. Um I'm sure there are
ways in which you can um process the
rare earths uh the rare earth ore in
which so you you can make sure you you
use as clean a process as possible for
you know uh for purifying or extracting
the the end product from the ore make
the process as clean as possible uh
don't dump the byproducts into the
ground process it or clean it or
whatever so I'm sure there are things
there are steps we can to ensure that
the damage is limited but there's going
to be some damage.
Basar Bandit says if a faction from
within Ghara Raja allegedly are doing
demographic re-engineering of EU a
possibility we discussed earlier with
intention of more EU control how
allegedly will they feel about this
India EU free trade deal.
What they will feel about the India EU
free trade deal will probably not be
very connected to what they are doing to
the EU.
See, whatever they're doing to the EU is
a long-term game they're playing. They
want to possibly
introduce
some cultural or religious elements into
Europe that in the future they would
like to control because you know of the
way things are.
But uh what what the EU is doing with
India, it's it's more immediate. The
demographic re-engineering game is a
long-term game. What the EU is doing is
more immediate. And obviously even that
the Americans let's let's say Gharaji or
or deep state is American they won't be
pleased about this because this gives
the EU options beyond the US right it
gives the EU access to a very major
market and it's win-win for India as
well as the EU it reduces the pressure
on both both entities India as well as
EU so uh what they will feel about this
is that they will not be pleased about
it and they may actually try and
pressurize the EU to pull out of this
deal you know or to maybe delay the deal
or something because the the
ratification of the deal will take some
time maybe 6 months maybe by the end of
this year by the time the Americans will
have plenty of time to pressurize the EU
for sure. So uh they're being displeased
about this FDA will actually have little
connection with whatever they are
allegedly doing about the demographic
re-engineering of Europe. Totally
different processes but they will be
displeased about it and they will try
and perhaps uh you know make this not
happen if they can.
Says why is it difficult to train cats
than dogs but relatively easy to train
tigers lions cat family then wolves
hyenas dog family. Wolves. Hyenas are
not dog family. Hyenas are feline
creatures. That's a great question.
First of all, okay. Uh let's see. Are
hyenas dogs or cats? Okay.
Are
hyenas a feline or canine? And you'll
find that they are felines.
Oh, they are higher cid whatever that
is. They are more closely related
related to cats than dogs. Okay. They
are closer to feliformia than cannormia
because of their evolutionary history.
They have a common ancestor with
Monguses, civet cats, civets and cats
despite their doglike appear appearance
from convergent evolution. So their
family is hyenas.
Okay. So that's they are neither cats
nor dogs but they are closer to cats
than to dogs. Okay. So why is it
difficult to train cats than dogs? I
mean there are dogs you can't train. We
have the Indian wild dog, the the dole.
You know what the dole looks like? It's
a red dog. Okay.
Dole dog.
This Indian wild dog, you can't train
it.
I mean, have you ever heard of somebody
domesticating this dog? These dogs live
in forests. They don't live in people's
backyards or they don't live in people's
houses. These these I don't Can Can
these guys be be domesticated? Let me
see. Uh can
uh be domesticated?
Let's see. Can it be domesticated?
Cannot be domesticated. They are social
and intelligent. They are wild and they
don't like human beings and so on, etc.
They are aggressive, unpredictable, and
unsuitable for pets. Pet pets despite
being a part of the dog species. It's a
dog. It's not a different species or a
subspecies. It's it's a dog. And yet,
you can't you can't adopt them. you
can't domesticate them. They are wild
and predictable and they will they don't
like to be with humans. So, it depends.
It it's the same species. It's a it's
it's a kind of dog. So, it's it's you
could say
you could say it's a different breed so
to say. It's not really different breed
land what's it called?
Land race. It's a different land race of
dog. Okay. But, uh you can domesticate
it. And now let's talk about cats versus
dogs. Very different creatures, right?
Very different creatures. Cats
essentially are nocturnal animals. First
of all, nocturnal. And you'll see
they're they always look lazy because in
the daytime they actually are supposed
to sleep. But because they have adapted
to living with humans, they kind of are
semi awake during the daytime. Sometimes
they're awake but they prefer to sleep.
But the moment it's dark, they are
totally active and they live a different
parallel life. Cats do.
And there are there are various cat
species. You have the standard house cat
which we humans are familiar with. We
have different species of wild cats. We
obviously have the uh what's it called?
The cheetah. We also have the lion.
Tigers and all. I mean look at lions and
tigers. They are almost the same size.
Tigers are slightly larger but they are
so different. Lions are so social and
all the ti tigers are solitary
creatures, right? So each species has
its own characteristics. I mean uh
chithas chias are you can you can um
domesticate a chita just like a house
cat. Chas don't really hurt humans and
chithas even vocalize like you know
meows like like house cats and they are
very easy to to domesticate. So these
are different species and they all have
their own characteristics. Our house
cats well they they are happy to live
with humans. They have no issue with
being friendly with humans, most of
them. But you can't train them. They
they won't be trained. You can train
dogs to do tricks, you know, stand on
two legs and do that and roll over and
all. Cats, no thank you. So, you know
what they say, you know, it's kind of a
funny thing to say, but uh you know,
humans
humans tame dogs, but cats tame humans.
That sort of thing. So, the cat is the
master of the house. It's not the human.
That sort of thing. And cats apparently
they see humans like a really dumb cat.
Dogs see the the human being as the
boss, right? Dogs are pack animals and
they always have the alpha dog. Wolves,
dogs, they all have the alpha dog, alpha
wolf. So dogs see humans as the alphas.
Cats see humans as dumb creatures. So
the way they see humans is different and
they are not aminable to being being uh
trained to do anything. They want
Riket says why does Russia consider
Ukraine NATO as a joining NATO as a red
line but not Finland as Estonia Latvia
which also shares border with Russia.
Good question once again. So let's take
a look at the borders of Russia. Yes.
Let's [snorts] take a look at borders.
Right. Okay. So
right. So here we are talking looking at
Eurasia. Let's go northwards. mouth of
India you have uh you know you have
Tajakistan then Kyhistan then Kazakhstan
then Russia right north of India now if
you go westwards then you have all these
neighboring nations of Russia Belarus
Ukraine these are historically part of
Russia or Slavic peoples the Belarusian
people are Slavic just like Russians the
Ukrainians are Slavic just like Russians
the Serbians are Slav Slavic people just
like Russians and then you have these
nations here Finland
Estonia Latvia Lithuania India, Norway,
Denmark, Sweden, etc. The the Baltic
nations and the Nordic nations. Okay.
So,
why is Ukraine joining joining NATO or
Red Line but not Finland? Well, multiple
reasons. Look, Ukraine was part of the
USSR. Ukraine is a Slavic nation, right?
And it's a much larger nation and NATO
has never had a presence there.
When it comes to Finland, Estonia,
Latvia, see even Estonia, Lithuania,
Latvia were part of the USSR, but they
are not Slavic peoples. They are
obviously Indo-Uropeans. So, some of
these languages are very closely related
to Sanskrit, which is a totally
different matter. But they are not
really Russians. They are not really
Slavic people. Their their culture etc
is different from the Slavic culture. Um
and Lithuania, Latia, Estonia are tiny
little nations
and uh so the Russians are not that
concerned about those nations. When it
comes to Finland or you know the other
Nordic nations once again totally
different culture, totally different
context in history. They were never part
of the USSR.
But Ukraine, it's a strategically
important nation, very large nation,
second largest nation in Europe. If you
exclude Russia, if you consider Russia
to be European uh and uh
and huge territory,
huge u the bread basket of Europe,
Slavic people once again. So because of
the these multiple factors and the fact
that Ukraine is the original Russia, I
mean the first ever capital city of the
Roose people, the Kievan RS was Kiev.
The original capital of the Roose people
was Kiev, not Moscow. Moscow comes much
later. Moscow comes like 400 500 years
later. The original capital was Kiev. So
because of historical reasons, because
of cultural reasons, because of ethnic
reasons and so on and so forth, all
these things, that's why Ukraine is a
red line. Those other nations are not
that important.
Okay. DN0 HR9879 says, "Why did Kushim
need
28,086
measures of Bali?
Love your content in your Norse skull.
Skull
skull.
I'm not aware of this now. This seems to
be some interesting folktale or
something. Let's find out. Kushiman
28,000 etc. measures of Bali. I'm not
aware of this. Let me learn what you're
talking about. So, who's Kushim? Will
that give us a clue? Who's Kushin?
Aha. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. The
earliest known recorded name of an
individual in human history. Are you
kidding me? Okay. Appearing on sugent
clay tablets dating around 3,400 to
3,000 BC. found in his ancient
Mesopotamia, modern Iraq. These tablets
are administrative records, suggesting
Kushin was an accountant or scribe
responsible for tracking barley rather
than than a king or a hero. The first
signature, the name appears on several
tablets dealing with the 29,086 measures
of barley. One tablet contains a note
interpreted as 29,086 measures of
barley, 36 37 months Kushim. So Kushim's
name highlights the writing was
initially developed for practical
economic purposes specifically tracking
resources rather than literature or
dealing with the rule deeds of rulers.
It's unclear if Kushim refers to a
specific person or is a job title for a
record keeper. Uh the name is
prominently highlighted in Yal Noha
Harare's book Sapiens. Okay. Sapiens to
illustrate the origins of writing and
bureaucracy. Okay. Okay. Okay. Got it.
So he probably was some kind of record
keeper and he his job was to you know
track the consignments and shipments of
Bali and so on. When it comes to
Harari's book, I haven't read it. I
tried reading it. I could not.
It wasn't for me. Hari, you know how
Hari approaches the human species. He
approaches the human species. I mean the
way he writes about the human species,
it's like, you know, um someone who is
doing a dissection is writing about, you
know, I mean someone's dead and the dead
the dead body is lying on your
dissection table. It's a cadaavver and
you are slicing it up and you're you
know clinically coldly talking about you
know all this stuff and just denying
that this is you say that this is just
an object lying in front of me these are
the organs and these are the um
characteristics I'm seeing and you deny
that this was a person that this person
had atma a soul all of that so you know
Harari's writing is cold
it's it's dismissive of the human spirit
and all I I can't stand his writing
actually he may He may sound very
intelligent to many people to me I I I
can't stand Harari's writing. Anyway,
I'm I'm glad that he wrote about Kushim
and that I was not aware of this. So
yeah, we don't know why Kushim needed
28,000 28,08 measure Bali probably he
was a record keeper tracking
consignments and storage and whatnot and
that's why I recorded this. There's also
the other guy right Naser Ayan Naser he
was a copper merchant and the world's
first recorded customer complaint is
about a naser uh selling delivering poor
grade of copper that's another
interesting story from there from
Mesopotamia
okay anik says Scott Basanti crying
because of FTA
is India handled you as
Look, let's not be all triumphant and
you know start bloating. The US is way
more powerful than India. They can even
if they want stop the India EU trade
deal. Okay, they can apply pressure on
Europe on the EU people on the key
people in Europe and who knows.
So Scott Bessent well Scott Bessant is
actually
well not as annoying as Howard Lutnik
but yeah
so he's upset. Trump is upset. The US uh
administration, the US uh Trump regime
is upset. His officials are upset and
they may actually do something about it.
They may actually apply pressure on the
EU. So let's not be all start
celebrating too early. Let it be let the
FDA become let the FDA be be ratified
and become operational then we can
gently celebrate. Anik says
India is dumping US treasury bonds and
buying more and more gold and silver. Is
India making itself sanctions proof? Is
India preparing for war? Look, US
Treasury bonds.
Yeah, it it's okay. So, we are dumping
US Treasury bonds. We're buying gold and
silver. Uh that doesn't make India
necessarily sanctions proof. What makes
you sanction proof is that if you can
bypass Swift, what is Swift? Swift is is
the system that the Americans control by
which you do uh transfers of large sums
of money across nations. The Swift
system. Okay, let's let's see what uh EI
has to say about Swift.
What is the Swift system? EI the Swift
society for worldwide interbank
financial telecommunication. It's a
secure global messaging network, not a
bank itself. Used by 11,000 plus
financial institutions in 200 plus
countries to securely transmit payment
instructions headquartered in Belgium.
essentially owned by the Americans or
controlled by the Americans. It
streamlines cross control crossber
transfers using standard standardized
BIC codes. I mean if you want to
transfer money as an individual to a
nation you have to enter a BIC code okay
for the bank that you're transferring to
and obviously the account details of the
person. So yeah, Swift/BIC codes.
Anybody who has done international
monetary uh transactions knows what
Swift and BIC codes are. Without Swift,
without access to Swift, you your
country essentially is cut off from the
global financial system, right? So Swift
is one of the big means of imposing
sanctions. You simply cut the nation off
from the Swift system and the nation
can't trade with the world because the
Americans control the system. So if
India wants to become sanctions proof,
India has to create or participate in
some kind of alternative to swift and
maybe there is something being done
about this India and the BRICS nations
and so on. Yeah. So that makes you
somewhat sanctions proof to some extent
to some extent which means that using
the alternative system you can trade
with certain countries but maybe not all
countries but maybe the ones you need to
and so on. Um so yeah India is obviously
buying more gold and India India has the
world's largest uh private gold
collection in the world. Indian ladies I
suppose. Yeah
it it's it's larger than all the gold
reserves of the top 10 countries put
together.
So we have that uh silver also is
important obviously. So is India
preparing for war? I think India is
preparing for all eventualities. Let's
put it that way. The India's preparing
for more volatility in the global
economic and financial order. It makes
sense the way things are going right
now. Anik says which why are countries
purchasing less US Treasury bonds? The
US is adding $1 trillion debt every 75
days. It will cross 50 trillion in 2026.
Where is this going?
See US Treasury bonds. What's a Treasury
bond? It's a bond, right?
A US Treasury bond is a piece of paper
that is worth a certain amount of money.
It says maybe $100, maybe thousand,
whatever, whatever. And if I am a
sovereign nation, let's say I'm India,
and I buy this one of these treasury
bonds, let's say worth 100 rupees, $100,
then the US owes me a $100.
Now, why do nations buy this treasury
bonds? Because historically, these
treasury bonds were were good
investments. you let's say you purchase
a million dollars in treasury bonds and
if the US dollar and the US e economy
are strong then in two three years it
may be worth $2 billion let's say
hypothetically right so these are these
used to be good investments but today
the way the Americans are printing money
recklessly these treasury bonds aren't
good investments that's why nations are
staying away from these treasury bonds
which means then that and the way this
whole thing is structured that's how the
US gains money that's how the US becomes
you
it's it's it's able to purchase things
from other nations and so on. Um so
because of the way the Americans have
been printing money recklessly the past
few years especially since Obama came to
power the US Treasury bonds are becoming
less and less attractive as investments
and that's why countries are now being
very cautious about whether to purchase
these bonds or not and people are
countries are now increasingly uh opting
not to purchase treasury bonds. Right?
So where is this going? The US economy
is a huge bobble. The US dollar is is
backed by only brute military power. It
has no real value of its own. It's just
paper. It's it's worthless paper.
Actually this entire global economy is
the US bullying other nations to assign
value to paper and by doing that they
are able to control the world. One day
this bubble is going to burst. So,
Han Sharma says, "I want to I just want
to leave a mark on those whom I talk to.
How do I do that and create an
interesting personality even though my
life is boring?" Continued, "How do I
make others want to know me and care
about me? While trying to do this, I
just end up copying personality of those
I find interesting." Uh, will telling
interesting stories help though I have
no such stories. What can I do to leave
a mark on people? What you can do to
leave a mark on people is do some
meaningful work. What makes a person
interesting? You have to ask yourself
this simple question. What makes a
person interesting? Is it the way the
person speaks?
I mean look, there are people who don't
really speak very well and yet they are
fascinating. Look at Elon Musk. He
doesn't have the most uh polished manner
of speaking, right? He stutters, he
stumbles, he does and all and yet he's
fascinating.
Okay?
He does leave a mark on every person he
speaks to.
Okay? It's not because he has got an
interesting personality. It's because he
has he's doing extremely meaningful work
which has made him very very rich, the
richest person in the world. So my point
is if you want to leave a mark on people
you talk to,
it's not by creating an interesting
personality.
Um it's not by copying the personality
of people you find interesting. Okay?
It's not by telling interesting stories.
It's by being yourself. By becoming a
person of substance.
So you have to do something meaningful.
Something that most people don't do. You
have to find something like that from
your you to first introspect. You to
think about what are the things that you
find interesting that you you find
motivating. Don't think about today. Go
back to the time when you were 5 years
old. Most people can remember things
from the when they were 5 years old.
What interested you when you were five?
What fascinated you? What did you want
to do when you grew up? Who did you want
to become when you grew up?
Those are the things that that will
motivate you for the rest of your life.
Not not various uh passing fads or
whatever. So find something meaningful,
some kind of mission that you need to go
on in your life. Okay? And uh maybe it
cannot be your career. Maybe perhaps for
for all for everybody you can't make
your your your passion your career but
you can keep it as a meaningful thing in
life and work on that construct
something build something create
something that will automatically make
you an interesting person okay then you
don't have to speak in a fascinating way
or something just be yourself and talk
about what you're doing your passion
will will shine through okay so telling
interesting stories what's the point
right what's the point. Whose stories
will you tell? You have to tell your
story. You have to talk about what
you're doing.
Uh so that's what you do. That's how you
leave a mark on people. Uh why are
fascinating people fascinating? It's not
because of the way they speak or the way
they dress or the way they look. It's
because of what they do. That's what
makes them fascinating. Every
fascinating person is doing something
meaningful, something that is impactful
and something that most people can't do.
That's what makes them interesting.
Think about all the people that you find
interesting, right? And ask yourself
what is it that this which makes this
person unique. Some of them may be good
speakers and all that. But it's not
generally that that makes them
interesting. There are many people who
are smooth talkers. No one cares. So be
an interesting person. Do something
meaningful and interesting. That is what
will make you uh leave a mark on
everyone you speak to. And it won't
leave a mark on everyone you speak to.
There is there will be some people who
don't care. Well, who cares about them,
right? Okay. All the best sir Anisharma.
Okay. Vidi Mana Vidi G says Nepa virus.
What's coming now? Especially for India.
Look Vidi G. The world is full of
viruses. Take a glass of sea water. This
is not sea water but take a glass of sea
water and put that under the electron
microscope. You'll you'll find new
viruses that humans have never seen
before. The world is full of viruses.
Viruses are genetic ideas. They're
small. The viruses have small strands of
DNA. Their their genome is typically
much smaller than the human genome. And
sometimes they do nothing. Most of the
times a virus does nothing nothing to to
humans. Sometimes they are kind of
beneficial to humans. Which is why if
you look at the human genome, a
significant percentage of the human
genome is actually absorbed viral
genome.
We have absorbed viral DNA and a lot of
the DNA is is part of our DNA today. But
there are some viruses that are bad
genetic ideas and that they kill their
hosts or or make life miserable for
their hosts and those are the bad ones
and it looks like this Nepa virus is one
of those nasty ones perhaps. Um is it
really becoming a problem in some parts
of India? I'm not sure what's coming for
especially for India. There's always
some viruses floating around that that
are potentially nasty. We have to be
careful about them to identify them and
take the measures to isolate them and so
on. Hopefully this doesn't become a big
deal.
That's all all I can say at this point
in time. I hope it doesn't become a big
deal. Yeah.
Anik says Rigveda mentions Sarasati as a
river in its prime. So what is the real
prime of Saraswati? 4,000 BC when
monsoon started declining or 10,000 uh
BC when satage goes east or 50,000 BC
when the Yamuna goes west as far as we
are concerned the last time the river
was in her prime is the real prime there
may have been other primes but from our
perspective look what are we interested
in all of us we are interested in having
a reliably reasonably
reasonably good date of the writing of
the riged
we want to figure out when the rigida
was first written. Okay. And from that
perspective which is the type the prime
of the saraspati we are interested in
the last time it was in its prime which
is about 6,000 BC. The river Saraspati
was last in her prime around 6,000 BC.
That's when the Indian rainy season
starts very gradually declining,
monotonically declining and the river
kind of dried out in the southern half
of its course half around 2,000 BC or
some around that time. So 6,000 BC is
the time the river was last in her
prime. There have been other it's it's
been a long-lasting river you know. So
all those other primes we are not
concerned about. The last time the river
was at her maximal prime which is about
6,000 BC. That's what we we are
interested in. Of course, it's it's had
all of that, right? The satlage goes
east and all that all of that. But
that's part of the older history which
is not that relevant for our purpose
which is the dating of the Riga. Harish
Sharma says, "How do I increase my
attention span whenever I'm taking a
lecture? After every two minutes, my
mind is wandering everywhere. I don't
even watch reals." How do you increase
your attention span whenever you are
watching a taking a lecture?
Well, one thing you can do is take
notes. Take notes. Tell yourself every
30 seconds I'll write down a line of
what I'm hearing the maybe the key
words, maybe the important points. So,
if you're doing something actively,
you're forced to pay attention. If
you're sitting and watching as if you're
watching a movie, your mind will wander.
But if you're doing something actively
like what is the guy saying or the lady
saying, "Ah, that's an important point.
Let me write it down." So write down the
key points that sort of thing thing stay
active active active. As long as as you
are actually actively doing something
your mind won't really be able to
wander. So that's what you do sir. Uh
Han Sharma says did you get a chance to
watch Tumbad? If yes tell us how you
feel about it. I still haven't watched
it. I'm not sure which uh OTT it's
available on and u uh yeah so I haven't
watched it yet but when I do watch it I
will let you all know for sure. I
obviously I know that it's a great
movie.
Right.
An Diviu says, "Sir, you always
recommend government reforms for
education. Why not focus our energies on
getting government out of the way and
starting groundup alternatives?" Uh,
okay. How do we do that is the question.
Look,
um, [snorts] in the current system, we
vote for the government, we pay taxes to
the government, and the government,
which is made up of our elected
representatives, carries out the work
for us. That's the deal.
And uh well in their wisdom they are not
concerned about education. They think
that the current education system is
fantastic.
Best best education system in the world.
Yes. Outstanding. NP 2020. Brilliant.
That's what they think. So in their mind
it is great. In their mind maybe I'm an
idiot. Okay. So then what do you do?
Focusing our energies on getting
government out of the way. How do you do
that? You're talking about what are you
talking about? Are you are you
suggesting we we carry out a people's
revolution?
You can't do that. I mean you can but
that that will not be great for the
country because if you have an internal
let's say completely hypothetical
internal revolution in the country
hypothetically I'm not saying I want it
then national security
becomes a casualty. Your neighbors will
start biting at your borders and take
out chunks of your territory.
Right? That's a very genuine
possibility. Your GDP will plummet. Your
economy will crash. Your industries will
will crash. There'll be chaos. Do you
want that? We don't want it. So, what
can we do to get the government out of
the way? We can't do get it get it out
of the way. So, the people we elect have
to make changes.
Or the alternative is that someday in
the future, maybe 20, 50, 100 years down
the in the future, some great leader
will emerge will take the nation by the
scruff of its neck and and just change
the system and impose a new system on
the on on the nation that will make the
nation better because currently we have
a rotten system actually, right?
Starting groundup alternatives. What can
we do to start a groundup alternative?
Create an groundup education system.
with that education system
will it help people let's say we start a
groundup alternative of a different
education system
as long as the current
job market is such that it demands
degrees if you create a new education
system it won't be that relevant
hopefully soon
um we will have a situation where you
know companies don't demand degrees they
demand your your experience they they'll
ask for what work have you done? What
are you capable of? What skills do you
have? In that case, in once that
happens, the education system will
slowly start becoming irrelevant.
So, it's easy to talk about these
things. Let's focus our energies on
getting the government out of the way.
But how do you practically do it? It's
almost next to impossible. That's just
the truth, right? I'm not being defeist
or whatever here. I'm not being
pessimistic. You can't take on the might
of the state and try to get the
government out of the way. Even if you
succeed, you're going to harm the nation
significantly. You know, don't do that.
MKUP says, "Does
INS vilization inch closer if does
India's vasilization inch closer if Iran
falls [snorts]
somewhat somewhat?" Yeah,
it it becomes slightly more likely that
India will get vasized if Iran falls to
some extent. Yeah, maybe 5%. Maybe so.
Slightly more.
Okay. Pranjal Chasia has gifted one
channel membership. Thank you very much
sir indeed. Thank you so much. Very kind
of you. Abisha Shivasam says your views
on Epstein files latest videos. I
haven't seen any of the videos.
I have seen whatever has come out on X
on on what was formerly called Twitter
the screenshots of whatever. I have not
even opened the links or whatever. And
uh what I have seen is that Trump is
mentioned gazillion times. He seems to
be one of the nastiest pieces of work on
the planet. Trump, okay, an absolute
I mean, I don't have the right words,
polite words for him to describe the
kind of person he is, Trump. And Howard
Lutnik is another sob.
So that's what I know about. I Nikki
Haley is involved. The Clintons, I'm
sure, are involved and so on so forth.
Elon Musk is dancing around the
periphery
and some Indian politicians are trying
to involve the Indian prime minister and
who so on but it's not going to work out
at all and some other Indian political
connections seem to be there which I
shall not mention here. Uh overall this
is what I'm aware of. I've just glanced
through things and I've been like
disgusted with what I've seen especially
Trump. Um I have not seen any of the
videos. Thank you. I am not going to
watch those. I have no interest in
watching I mean spoiling my day and
spoiling my appetite by watching those
videos. I'm not going to watch that.
Uh Net Grapp says age is a barrier to
education in India but not in the US.
I'm I've heard of a few people who
complete their PhDs when they they're in
their 60s or whatever. So it looks like
at least for for the higher education
PhD or whatever you can do it when
you're in your 60s or even 70s I
suppose. um when it comes to other
degrees for let's say a master's degree
or a bachelor's degree do is there you
know maximum age limit or something okay
let's see let's find out let's let's
Google this
um does India have a limit does India
have an age
limit for
bachelor degree uh bachelor degree let's
Do we have no maximum age limit? Uh
there's a minimum age limit apparently.
Yeah, minimum age of 17 or 18. But what
if I'm a super genius at the age of 12?
I want to do a bachelor's degree. They
won't allow me. That is sad. So there is
no u maximum. No, there's no upper age
limit. What about a master's degree?
Master's degree. Do we have something?
Generally there's no upper age limit.
Okay. No general age barrier. No age
limit uh no restrictions
uh some in rare cases specific
specialized or government things may
have age restrictions as part of their
their uh institutions eligibility
criteria. What about um um 12th standard
uh pass degree? Let's see. Do we have
that? Generally no upper age limit. So
even at the age of 35, you can get get
your 12th standard done I suppose. Uh
what about 10th? 10th.
Let's see. Generally no maximum. Okay.
So okay, we get it. All right. All
right. All right. So age is a barrier to
education in India. Not quite. Right. I
mean there's no official barrier.
Um
yeah that's what we just saw. Maybe
you're trying to say something else but
I'm not able to get what something else
could be. What we have seen is that
there officially are no major barriers.
Pratik Shinoi says who's winning the
proxy war in Myanmar? Is India involved?
India is not involved India is a
spectator
or if India is involved it may not be
involved in the best possible way. Okay.
I mean what's happening in Manipur is is
is a disaster.
Right now the media is not watching it
because because the situation seems to
have stabilized in the absolutely wrong
way. It's the many person of foreign
occupation at least half of it and the
native people are are suffering. Now
who's winning the proxy war in Myanmar?
I haven't been keeping track of what's
happening. There are all these little
factions who are fighting each other. I
think the government has kind of
stabilized the situation to some extent.
The government that's based out of
Nyapido. Uh earlier the capital used to
be Yangon Rangun now it's Nyapida. So I
think uh there is some stabilization
that's happened. It's not like the proxy
war isn't raging that much but the
northern uh the Chinese are definitely
involved in the northern factions right
and the northern factions are selling
the rare earths to the Chinese and uh
India may be involved in some you know
diplomatic way or whatever to some
extent but yeah we aren't fighting or or
taking sides as far as I know in the
fighting I could be wrong about that but
not officially taking sides not
officially taking sides Unofficially God
knows what we are doing.
Shashwat Ames says what are the
difficulties of the next leader or prime
minister of India? What are the
difficulties the next leader or prime
minister of India would face? PM will
have PM Modi will have to choose his
successor someday.
Well, the prime minister Mr. Modi can
choose a successor but he can only
choose a a candidate for his successor.
The people have to vote for that person,
right? It's not like uh in the Chinese
Communist Party when the polit bureau
decides who's the next next leader. It's
not like uh a dynastic rule where the
king decides who the next which of his
sons is going to be the next ruler.
Um so what are the difficulties the next
leader in the prime or prime prime
minister of India will face whoever it
is? Well,
[laughter]
I mean, it remains to be seen if they
see it as a difficulty or as an asset. I
mean, if they think that the bureaucracy
is an asset, then that's not a
difficulty for them. But if they really
want to reform the country and reform
the bureaucracy, that's going to be a
big hurdle for them, a big difficulty.
If they're trying to reform the
bureaucracy, they're going to face all
kinds of issues and lack of cooperation
and whatnot potentially. Right? I'm not
saying the bureaucracy is a necessarily
evil or bad thing. There are plenty of
fantastic great people in the
bureaucracy, but overall it's it's
in it's in desperate need of reforms. Um
various other institutions that I shall
not name here may not cooperate are
definitely
um in you know once again crying need of
reform. uh getting the states to
cooperate because India is a very
federal nation and a lot of um you know
a lot of areas are states state subjects
so even if the government central
government wants to do these certain
things the states may not cooperate and
there's nothing you can do about it
right they to wait another five years
for the government to hopefully change
potentially so these are the these are
the problems that India faces every
leader of India faces and of course
these are the internal problems I'm
talking about the the education system.
Obviously, I keep on talking about that.
No one cares, I suppose. Um, the quality
of the population, the population is is
is hooked to the drug of of uh of of
cash transfers,
unconditional cash transfers.
I mean, if you want to give cash
transfers to people, those have to be
conditional, right? Some some
requirements have to be met, but no,
this is all unconditional. So, some of
these issues we only have created, this
government has created. So all these
issues the next leader will have to
face. And if they are some are a if that
person is a leader who wants to reform
the country, they're going to face
significant problems. If the person is
someone who thinks the country is in the
best shape possible, no problems
whatsoever. Keep it going another 5
years.
Okay. Hyphen says, uh, dumb question.
No, there's no dumb questions. I know
wormholes are like shortcuts, but does
the speed of light speed limit still
apply inside of a wormhole? Thank you.
Yes, it does apply. The speed limit the
speed of light limit does apply inside a
wormhole. You can't break the limit the
speed limit the limit of the speed of
light inside a wormhole. A wormhole is
is is like a bridge actually more than a
shortcut. They are called Einstein holes
and bridges and yeah if if matter is
traveling inside a wormhole it can't
break the speed limit the speed of light
it can't. Okay but that's all
hypothetical. Nobody has actually seen a
wormhole. We don't even know if they
like take question study that the
wormholes want to snap shut immediately
and turn into two black holes. But how
do you keep them open is a question. So
you may need exotic matter for that.
Maybe a negative mass matter which
nobody has ever seen. But according to
the equations of physics, you can have
negative mass matter, right?
Um you can also use topological defects
like um uh cosmic strings
u to keep our mole potentially open but
these are all exotic matter that nobody
has seen but anyway anyhow to answer
your question the speed limit does apply
you can't break the speed limit inside
of our molehuran
says uh watched the movie arrival which
introduced me to separ hypothesis on how
language change perceptions. Could
Sanskrit and meditation and our learning
methods be the reason why our ancestors
were so brilliant? Okay, I am not very
familiar with this saper warf
hypothesis. Okay, let's see.
Warf uh what am I doing? WARF
hypothesis. Okay, let's see what it
says. The saper warf hypothesis or
linguistic relativity proposes that the
language a person speaks influences or
determines how they perceive and think
about the world. Oh, I completely agree
with that. And people who think
primarily pime primarily in English are
dumber, stupider than people who think
primarily in Sanskrit. No question about
that. So, uh the language a person
speaks suggests that no this this
hypothesis suggests that grammatical and
lexical structures shape cognitive
patterns and worldviews making it easier
or harder to conceptualize certain ideas
and so on. [clears throat] I completely
agree with this. I mean, I've not heard
of this hypothesis, like I said, but
it makes sense. I've I've thought about
it along those lines, but not calling it
the saber warf hypothesis. Of course,
the language you speak influences the
way way you think, it influences how
intelligent or stupid you are. It does.
If you speak a a crude language like
English, if that is your primary
language, you're going to be a little
lower in intelligence and cognition and
what not
than somebody who speaks a high language
like Sanskrit. But today, nobody speaks
Sanskrit. Fortunately for the English
speakers, we have killed Sanskrit in
India. It survives as the vocabulary of
the existing languages. But nobody
actually speaks Sanskrit anymore. maybe
a handful of people who speak it as the
primary language I suppose.
So I completely agree that Sanskrit and
meditation and our learning methods were
the reasons why our ancestors were so
brilliant and and because we no longer
speak Sanskrit. We no longer meditate
and we have abandoned our indigenous
learning methods. That's why Indians are
so much lower in intelligence today
compared to our ancestors. No question
about that. I completely agree with you.
Totally. the movie Arrival. Well, yeah,
I saw that.
It's more of an art film masquerading as
a science fiction film and that's my
opinion and it's an opinion that is not
very popular but anyway yeah so I agree.
Vin says they preach atheism and
liberalism while worshiping pagan things
of Mesopotamia and canonite uh that do
wrongly interpretation horrific things
in email. Yeah, the Epstein files. These
people are monsters. They are
pedophiles. They're cannibals. They're
murderers. They're torturers. They are
the most despicable human beings you can
imagine. And they are ruling the most
powerful country in the world. And even
though this has been all released to the
public, I doubt if anyone's going to be
public going to be punished. I don't
think uh Trump is going to be punished.
I don't think uh Latnik is going to be
punished. I don't think the Clintons
will be punished. I don't think u
um Nikki Haley is going to face any real
issues,
right? They're flaunting their
invincibility to the world.
So the nation that lectures the rest of
the world about human rights and freedom
and democracy and you know adopts this
morally superior stance. This is the
most depraved nation in the world. This
nation
was created out of genocide and slavery
and now their rulers
are are pedophiles and and murderers and
and cannibals and whatnot. I mean that's
the truth.
Amisha says it's my birthday tomorrow.
Well happy birthday to you in advance
madam. Happy birthday. What's your best
advice for me to excel as a student and
grow as an individual?
My best advice
to excel as a student and grow as an
individual. How to grow as an
individual? You have to be you have to
understand who you are. See most of us
we don't even know who we are.
Most people
the things they say they are not the
product of their own thinking.
Most most people in the world they will
absorb things from here there etc etc
and then they will regurgitate that as
if that is their own thinking but they
have no original thoughts of their own
um and they don't even know who they are
who they really are scared to spend
three three hours in the room alone by
themselves they're scared so most people
are like that so I would say you need to
get in touch with who you really are you
spend time alone you need to understand
who you are and that will then inform
you as to what decisions to take in life
and what directions to go in. So, so uh
that's one advice. That's how you grow
as an individual by by introspecting.
It's not you should spend 5 days out of
seven introspecting. No, once in a while
do that. Try and think about who you
really are and what you you know what
you're really about and all that. Uh how
to excel as a student? How to excel as a
student? If first advice, don't spend
your entire day studying. You'll go
crazy.
Okay? your parents I mean many parents
will tell students at least 8 hours a
day you have to study ideally 12 hours a
day you wake up study study until you
sleep then go to sleep then next day
repeat rinse and repeat that is terrible
advice
[clears throat] you should force
yourself to study only within a certain
time frame even if the exam is coming in
two weeks time last 5 days maybe you can
study 8 12 hours a day only the last few
days that will ensure you don't get
burned out mentally
Otherwise you should ideally not study
more than four to six maybe four hours a
day. If you are reasonably intelligent
four hours a day is enough. And by
forcing yourself to do all your study in
a in a certain amount of time you'll
actually maximize
the the the outcomes of your study. And
that way you'll also be able to balance
your out of balance your life and do
interesting things beyond studying. So
I'm not saying it should be four hours.
You can decide whether it whether it's 4
hours or 6 hours or 3 hours or whatever.
But that's how you excel as a student.
You don't excel as a student by spending
your entire time studying, right? Um
yeah. All right. Happy birthday. Do well
as always. Best wishes.
Ainta Anand says, "Hep G wrote article
for make in India. Now we know why our
lobbying failed. Epstein was also
targeting Indian women and after the
USSR fall targeted Slavic women reason
for children removal by Russians mother
of New York City mayor is also in the
files okay you mentioned a lot of things
here uh Hardep Singh Puri so when
everyone's writing about all kinds of
nasty disgusting things to epsteep Singh
Puri G is writing about making India man
he was educated so Hardep Singh Puri the
minister right he does figure in the
epste files how how does he figure he's
lobbying for India is lobbying for
making India
the one clean guy in the extinction file
I suppose noteping puri um I don't know
if that's why our lobbying failed or
whatever did our lobbying fail okay the
Americans obviously see our lobbying in
the US will not work well because the
Americans are pro Pakistan and they
don't want India to do well that's why
lobbying fails it if you have a smarter
minister your lobbying will not work no
matter who you have the Americans don't
want India to succeed this is something
you need to all understand. Okay. Now,
Epstein was targeting Indian women.
Okay. I've not seen that part of the
Epstein files, but I'm sure he must have
targeted all kinds of women. Uh and they
would have targeted Slavic women. Of
course, where there's misfortune, the
vultures will circle, right? The
vultures, the western vultures will
circle wherever there is misfortune.
After there was an earthquake in Nepal,
the Christian missionaries started
circling like vultures and they have
successfully converted God knows how
many Nepales after that. So these
vultures they they they feed on
misfortune.
So yeah they I suppose lots of Slavic
women were targeted and brought to the
US and God knows what happened to them.
Yeah. Uh reason for children removal by
Russians. I don't know about that.
Mother of Okay. So the New York City
mayor is this Zoharan Mani character.
His mother is Miran. Miran Naer the
filmmaker and she was once married to a
guy named Epstein but a different
Epstein. And then she married the guy
who allegedly is Zoharan Mandani's
father and she is in the Epstein files.
Uh that's what I know. I don't know in
what capacity or what to what activities
she's in the files but she's in the
files. Nasty stuff. Okay. Vive Singh
says uh how can the untapped potential
of states like UP, Uttar Pradesh, Madhya
Pradesh, Bihar etc be used? Their key
for 10 10% of GDP growth is they are a
massive workforce. See
the states
first of all they need top quality
leadership that's one thing you need so
at least Uttar Pradesh I know that the
leadership is great it's Yogi Aditina G
who's the leader I think he's a great
leader I mean a gigantic state like
Uttar Pradesh with the population higher
than the US he's managing that and so
there is that okay so first of all you
need high quality leadership I'm not
sure who's the chief minister of Madhya
Pradesh and Bihar. Let's find out. Okay.
See, as you know, I'm not keeping track
of internal issues in India. Uh MPCM,
who's this MPCM? Moanov. Okay. I'm not
aware of uh his his work, so I would not
comment about that. Bhar
who's the Bihar CM. Okay. Mr. Nitesh
Kubar, a pretty well-known gentleman.
So, first thing you need is high quality
leadership. Second,
you need to end the alleged corruption
that may exist. Uh what else can you do?
You have all states compete with each
other for per capita GDP or the highest
GDP growth in the country. Compete in a
healthy manner, right? You have all the
states compete with each other uh for
the most amount of investment they can
they can garner uh for the for the
highest GDP growth, for u the maximum
amount of manufacturing they are doing
and so on. So there are all kinds of
creative ways to do it. Each state can
have multiple special economic zones,
sees that's how the Chinese, you know,
jump started their economy. You can do
all kinds of creative things in India.
If you really want the nation to grow
this un massive untapped potential,
especially in places like Bihar, Magad,
Kamar, that is that is the old that is
the historic heartline of India. That's
where all the great empires came from,
right? The Moria Empire, the Gupta
Empire, that's Mad. And today look at
the state of the situation in Bihar. I
mean there's so much potential there. So
Ashoto Dar says
government budget rare earth corridor.
How important is securing
met cap?
Securing met cap. How much time do we
have before China weaponizes it?
Government budget rare earth corridor.
Okay. So there is I I haven't seen the
budget. Okay. By the way, I haven't seen
the budget. I am not a if you ask me
about the budget, I will not know what
to say because I haven't studied it.
It's it's come out today, right? The new
budget. Uh so I'm not aware of this rare
earth corridors thing. So I can't say
about that. How important is securing
metrif cap? What's a met cap, sir?
What's a metrif cap?
How important is securing a met cap?
Uh what's a met cap? I'm I'm not sure.
Sir, I'm so sorry. I probably I'm dumb.
I'm not able to understand what a met
cap is.
Metal
riff cap. I I'm I'm so sorry. I'm not
able to get it. Sorry. Sergeant Skylan
says, "Hi. Well, hello. Does India
really benefit from having defense
platforms from multiple countries
instead of a single country? Uh, does it
cause communication issues? It doesn't
cause communication issues. It causes
logistical issues.
Let's say you're talking about the Air
Force. The Air Force, what kind of
aircraft does the Air Force have? The
MiG 21 is now phased out. We have the
Jaguars, we have the Mirage 2000s. Um,
we have Mig 29s, we have Sukoy 30 30
MKIs, we have the Tajis aircraft. So
that's at least five different kinds of
fighter planes. Then we have various
kinds of so if you have five different
kinds of fighter planes they all have
different characteristics they used for
different purposes but if you have lots
of different kinds of fighter planes you
need different you know you need to
supply them with spare parts of course
after some time you need to change spare
parts for a fighter plane or any
aircraft so you will need so many
different supply lines but if all your
manufacturing is done all the equipment
is manufactured let's say in one country
India itself then is so much easier to
get all the spare parts Right?
For if you are buying some uh defense
equipment, let's say the Chinook
helicopters from the Americans, then
there there's going to be additional
layers of bureaucracy to get the stuff
that you know that you want. Maybe the
Americans are unleashed with you. Then
they will delay the supply of the spares
and so on, right? So it's a problem. So
ideally, you want everything to be
manufactured in your own country.
That's the ideal situation, right? Um in
that case there's not going to be any
issue. So it's not about communication
issues. It's about logistical issues.
It's about spare parts and it's also
about politics and geopolitics you know
diplomacy as well. Prattana says Indians
were making fun of Pakistan a few years
ago for JF17's inferior Russian engine
but they are able to export it and fly
it but our thing is kind of dead. Uh
which thing is kind of dead?
You're talking about the Indian engine,
the cavary engine. I'm not sure what
this what the deal is with the cover
engine but apparently we are going ahead
with Safhon the French company to
manufacture a completely new engine
which will serve um you know which will
be the right one for our requirements
that will take a few years.
The JF7 uses a Russian engine. Now I'm
not aware of Indians making fun of the
Pakistanis and the JF7. The JF7 is a
decent aircraft. I suppose it's a
derivative of the big 21.
So the the Chinese took the Mig 21 and
you know improved upon it and created
this JF7 and that's what the Pakistanis
fly and the Chinese obviously for the
longest time they didn't not have their
own jet engines that's why it uses
Russian engines. Um have the Pakistanis
exported the JF7 somewhere? I'm not
sure. Maybe a couple of nations may have
taken it. So okay good for the
Pakistanis.
uh our engine the caviri engine it has
never got under sufficient funding and I
don't know what the such a story is with
cowi but yeah we are going with u new
French deal so we'll see about that
simply aweb says what exactly led to
ultimate breakin what exactly led to
ultimate breakin in India was it because
we were too kind that we forgave
multiple times or we became arrogant
also Indian history book recommendations
If you want Indian history book
recommendations,
well, I'm going to have to uh
I'm going to have to
uh point you towards my older videos for
history book recommendations. First of
all, let's do that. Okay.
Uh you go to my channel. Here's my
channel on the screen. You go to the
videos tab that we are on. You go to the
oldest
And you see these these these cringe
thumbnails.
Uh which are the best books for learning
Indian history? It's a 13-minute video.
I've got some recommendations there. Uh
so so that is the deal. Now what led to
the ultimate breakin in India? Are you
talking about invasions of India? Um was
it because we were too kind to be
forgive multiple times? No, it is none
of these things. It is because we were
not politically unified under a single
empire.
It's because we were politically
fragmented. At the time when the Turks
started invading, attempting to invade
India, you did not have a single empire
in India like during the Morian period
or the Gupta period and so on or the
Kushan period. That's when the whole of
the subcontinent was unified under a
single empire. When you had that
situation in India, nobody could invade
you. But when the Turks started invading
10,000 AD approximately
before that actually before that
at that time India was divided into
small kingdoms and that's why because we
were not politically unified that's why
the Turks eventually started gradually
succeeding okay that's what happened
slow that's a great name like fast snail
[laughter] thank you so much thank you
anu says why didn't the US ensure its
European and East Asian vasals
maintained enough relative power to
offset the rise of China seeks like a
seems like a geopolitical blunder. The
Americans had gone had grown very
complacent. So they started the
Americans started aiding and abetting
and midwifing the rise of China um after
somewhere around the early 1970s. Okay.
In 1969, the Chinese and the uh Russians
the Soviets almost went to war and the
Americans saved the Chinese from being
nuked by the Soviets and that's when the
the process of the the begins the thaw
between the two countries. Eventually,
China starts very cautiously, very
gradually opening up its economy and and
and starting they start manufacturing
stuff for the Americans in China in
Chinese factories starting with
screwdriver stuff, you know, very basic
assembly and all but eventually they
they become slowly bigger in 1990s
onwards they start shooting up their
economy. So the Americans were under the
delusion that if the Chinese uh economy
is allowed to grow and China becomes
gradually more prosperous they Americans
were under under the illusion that China
will then become democratic. I mean they
actually believe that nonsense and
that's why they did not
make their uh other vasa of the region
Japan, South Korea etc stronger. They
actually weakened Japan 1990s onwards
1980s onwards right they weakened Japan
they they did the plaza accords that
slowly gradually deflated and shrank and
sank the the Japanese economy. Japan is
now a middle-income nation. It's no
longer a high income nation. The
Americans did that to Japan.
So the Americans were deluded. I suppose
they thought that the Chinese will
become democratic. Well, the exact
opposite happened. China has become an
empire.
Okay. Rajuran Rajar Rajar says, "By the
way, no Epstein file leak from September
1 only October and November."
September01.
Only October and November. Okay. I'm not
aware of that. Maybe that's an
interesting point. Yeah.
Okay. Rajun Rajar says, "Last time you
were pro proven wrong besides the
Iranian invasion." Ah, last time I was
proven wrong.
Um, last time I was proven wrong was one
of the times recently I was pro proven
wrong was when I said that India that
operation Synindur will will cause a
change of territory. I have this tweet.
Okay, you want to see me proven wrong.
You enjoy that? Does it make you happy?
Yeah. Let me make you happy then. Give
me a second. Let me pull up Twitter
and let's go to my profile.
Okay. Let me please you to show you how
I was pro wrong. So, I have this Twitter
account. Um, and we go to May.
Uh, let's say one second. Let me just
search for it. We are at war. Uh,
we are at war.
Let's see. Do we find that? No, the
Twitter search isn't great actually.
Let's see. War.
Um, war, war, war. Okay, this one. So,
here is me being proven wrong. We are at
war, friends. Within the next 12, two to
14 days, India will inflict in inflict a
comprehensive military defeat on
Pakistan. The borders will change
permanently. Clearly, I was wrong.
Clearly, I was too optimistic. Does that
please you? Are you pleased now?
[laughter]
All right.
V Hung Kuran says, "Hello, Abjit. How
are you doing?" I'm doing great. How are
you doing? I hope you're doing good. I
had a question. What exactly lies in the
region between the two entrances of a
wormhole? Also, can a collapsing and
unstable wormhole turn into a black
hole? Let me answer the second one
first. A collapsing and unstable
wormhole. All wormholes by definition
are actually unstable. They will not
turn into a black hole. They will turn
into two black holes. So, you have a
wormhole like this. Uh let's let's see
the an illustration of a wormhole on on
on Google. Yeah. Uh wormhole.
Okay. So these are your artistic
definition representations of wormholes.
But see over here you have okay this is
a this is science fiction. Sorry other
universe. Uh let us where can I find a
simple simple diagram of a wormhole.
Okay, here we have a wormhole. There's a
left entrance and a right entrance,
right? And in between there's there's
this bridge, the neck of the wormhole.
Wormholes want to the the the neck the
neck of the wormhole wants to snap shut
as soon as possible. Okay. So, what
happens is that wormholes are unstable
and the neck snaps shut and that gives
rise to two black holes. That's what
happens. So those two entrances become
two black holes and that's what happens.
I mean as per the equations. Okay. Uh so
what exactly lies in the region between
the two entrances of the wormhole? The
neck the throat of the wormhole
which is the region that connects these
two disparate regions of spaceime. It's
it's like a shortcut you can say right.
It's like a tunnel that you can go
through. Well that's what science
fiction movies tell you. But actually
it's unstable and it snaps shut
and that gives you two black holes.
So as long as the tunnel the the throat
exists you have a tunnel essentially or
a shortcut between two very vastly
disperate regions of spaceime that's
what you have
praumar says should India lead a group
like the OIC to protect Hindu Buddhist
and dharmic cultures safeguard
communities and strengthen times ties
among dharmic nations I would love if
that happens but the government of India
is a secular government and it will
never do this
as a secular government you can only
appease the external religions that are
that exist in the country. You can't
appease the indigenous religions or if
you appease indigenous religions, you
can't appease what is called Hinduism.
You can appease Buddhism, Sikhism,
Janism, whatever elseism, but you can
never appease Hinduism. See, India is a
Hindu phobic apartheid state.
India is the world's most hindophobic
country. This will never happen. Never
happen.
So, it's just the truth. Yeah.
Virtually present says US pays more
interest on debt than their defense
budget. Countries aren't buying bonds
after the Russia asset freeze. AI says
they AI says they can't just print
dollars. Thoughts big fan. Thank you.
You're very welcome. Thank you very
much. Um
countries. Yeah. So now
those Treasury bonds are not that
attractive. Nations aren't buying those
treasury bonds and that's a problem for
the US. Now, what how do how to run the
scam? Now, that's the question. The US
dollar scam, the dollar is a scam. It's
it's it's a bubble, right? It's a
worthless piece of paper, but it has
value because the Americans enforce that
the value of the dollar through their
military muscle. Um,
but you now increasingly see nations
move away from the dollar. You have the
Saudis selling oil to China and getting
yuan in exchange instead of dollars. uh
you have the India EU trade deal which
is obviously not going to be in dollars
right obviously it's the India and the
EU India is purchasing Russian oil in
rupees
the BRICS nations also don't want the
dollar US dollar nations are selling off
their US dollar assets and purchasing
gold and so on right so u
eventually the world will move away from
the US dollar which is a complete scam
that's why so many nations are now going
after gold physical gold. Um, so my
thoughts, what are my thoughts? This
entire
thing, the entire global economic order
that is that is based on the supremacy
of the US dollar, it's a scam. And this
this scam has allowed the US to print
worthless paper money and buy real
things in exchange from from the rest of
the world in exchange for pieces of
paper. It's a scam,
right? And the sooner it ends, the
better it is for the rest of the world.
And AI says they can't just print
dollars. They can print dollars. I mean,
they can create virtual imaginary
dollars in computers and turn them into
real currency. They can. I I'm not sure
what AI actually means by that, but the
Americans, they virtually print billions
of dollars every day.
Okay. Aman Kumar Dhankar says the naval
buildup can even look east also a naval
buildup can look 360°
if there's a naval buildup by the
Americans in the sea of Saashtra which
they call the Arabian Sea right let's
say there's a naval build up by the
Americans in the in the sea of Saashtra
right this place here well it can look
west it can look at Oman and Yemen it
can look at the Gulf of Oman it can look
at the Hormmo state it can look
northwest at Iran
It can even look east. It can even look
south. So it is what it is. Yes. It is
what it is.
It can look east. Okay. Prardana says on
UPI Hapl group R1B origin is east of
Iran. That is so naughty.
Very naughty. How can it be east of
Iran? That's a very naughty place, isn't
it? [laughter] Hlo group A R A R A R A R
A R A R A R A R A R A RB the HLO group
of the Yamnaya. The so-called Yamna. So
what is upedia? First of all, let's find
out what is upedia.
UPedia ecology, map, statistics, etc.
European European prehistory. Okay,
let's see what about R1B. R1B HL group
R1B YDNA.
So
ital let us see. Oh, what am I doing?
I'm I'm showing you something else. Give
me a second. Okay, I was aware the map
was still on the screen. Okay. So I've
opened updia and I have this thing about
uh hypoglob yDna u origins and history
hypstar in north Asia. Okay. Okay etc
etc. Raavan blah blah blah. The oldest
forms in R1B are found dispersed at very
low frequencies from Western Europe to
India. Vast region.
Uh, Haplo, R1B, Western,
South Asians. Um,
three main branches all seem to have
stemmed from the Middle East.
Okay. So, it has got various ways of
looking at this. But if it says that it
was the origin was east of Iran, well
that's a very naughty statement to make
because that kind of destroys the arin
invasion, migration, tourism, picnic
theory, right? Nan Parik says, "Where
did you get your PhD from?" I do not
have a PhD. I almost got got a PhD
almost. I submitted my PhD thesis, but
at the end of the day, I never got the
PhD. So I don't have one even though I
did all the work.
Raml Buju says good deeds done by Gandhi
and Nehu for India. No.
Good deeds done by Gandhi and Neu for
India. No,
you tell me.
Uh Arian Sorti says, "Does India hold
air superiority over Pakistan?" India
does because of its overwhelming missile
advantage.
Okay. And also the air Indian air force
is overall superior to the Pakistani air
force somewhat not by a great deal but
the missile advantage we have is
overwhelming and that's why we have air
superiority over the Pakistanis
right I mean uh how did we achieve air
superiority during operation sindur
through those missile and drone strikes
initially it's only after softening up
the Pakistanis and wiping out their air
defense radars and all that's when the
Indian air force probably was was
allowed to go and was was able to go and
strike at will. That's on day three or
something. So yeah, we do have air
superiority because of our missile
advantage.
J no KJ Wonders says who is a
financially independent man. A
financially independent man is somebody
who doesn't have to take orders from
anyone that be here and so and so time
and spend these many hours working for
me. That sort of thing. If you're
financially independent, you can decide
what you want to do with your life. If
today morning you wake up and say that
I'll go and watch three movies, you can
go and watch three movies. If today
morning you wake up and say, you know
what, I want to travel to so and so
place, you can do it. That's a
financially independent person. Some are
more independent. Some somebody could
say that tomorrow morning I want to wake
up and go to Switzerland. You could do
that. For some people it may be tomorrow
morning I'll go and uh visit the next
city. So different levels of financial
independence. But financial independence
means you are not under any obligation
to anybody. You have no debt. And
secondly,
you can live your life without having to
work. That is financially financial
independence. Actually uh financially
independent of also means that you know
what you are not for those of you who
are starting out in life. Financial
independence means having a source of
income for which you have to work which
means you are no longer financially
dependent on your parents or family.
That's also a form of financial
independence. But for that you have to
work. But genuine financial independence
means you don't have to work. You do
what you enjoy. And even if you don't
work, you have sufficient money to to
take care of your life. So that is the
real financial independence.
Prataradana says it's first fair and no
engine delivered by GE. Yeah. You see
that's how reliable our American friends
are. We have a we have a deal. We we
have paid the money but they are not
delivering engines. They are trying to
kill the the program and
shame on India for believing them.
Shame on India for for actually
believing that if you sign a contract
with the Americans they will honor it.
Seriously
so incredibly shortsighted of the
government of India
for actually believing that the
Americans won't use these things to arm
twist India.
Yeah, we are learning the hard way
through the through pain.
I am Pratish says, "Is quantum
technology the future? Quantum computing
and quantum machine learning? Where does
India stand? Where should I pursue MSE
in IT at TUM Germany or in India amid
global tensions?"
Uh first of all to answer your other
second question, where should you pursue
MSSE? pursing your MSE in the best
university you can get into
and I promise you if you can get into
any university outside of India it's
going to be better than Indian
universities especially if it's a
western university if it is western if
it is TUM Germany I don't know what TUM
Germany is but if it's T if it's in
Germany it probably is going to be
better than any Indian university in
including IIT and whatn not the Indian
education system is garbage it is trash
so I will recommend to all students try
to go abroad code for education if you
can afford it otherwise please don't do
it if you can't afford it if your
parents you don't want your parents to
take huge loans right
um so if if that's the case then I would
say stay in India but if you can get get
a scholarship or if you can your parents
can afford it or if you can afford it
then go and get an education outside of
India because western education is
always superior to the garbage trashy
Indian education system uh that's my
deal about where to get your MS MSC from
uh even if you have global tensions and
all you can still get a degree in a
foreign country and if you if required
come back to India if you can afford it
as always. Now is quantum technology the
future? Are quantum technologies the
future? Even slowly quantum technologies
will become more and more u you know
available
and uh eventually affordable. So right
now look you can't have a phone that
runs on a quantum computing chip right
it's it's your classical standard
computing chip that it runs on but
eventually in maybe 15 20 years you may
have maybe not phones but computers that
may have quantum computing abilities so
eventually it's going to become more and
more widespread quantum computing
quantum technologies right and it's not
for everything I mean if you want to do
your regular work you don't need quantum
computer for that quantum computers will
have very specific applications.
So yeah, eventually it's going to become
widely adopted. No question about that.
Quantum computing, quantum machine, I'm
not sure about quantum machine learning.
I've not thought about that. But quantum
computing, yes. Right. There are some
problems that your standard classical
computers can't solve or can't solve any
in a reasonable amount of time. And
quantum computers can do that because of
the quantum properties that are used
quantum superposition, entanglement and
all that. Um so yeah it is going to be
the future. Not everything is going to
be quantum computing but some of the
things that you will have quantum
computers computers take care of that
right. Provin J says there is a tweet
dated 171125 still present of Mr. Ashwin
Vashnov showing Bhutan as a part of
India in the map. Has India Bhutan
reached any kind of agreement or
understanding? Let's find out. Uh it is
a tweet by Mr. Ashwini Vnau. Okay.
Ashwini Wnau.
Okay. Where is his Twitter? Where's his
Twitter? His Twitter is here. So, his
Twitter, his tweet is from 171125.
Let's find out. Let's just scroll down.
Scroll down. 171125. He tweets a lot,
does he? Oh god, that's going to be a
while.
Um, January.
Oh, okay. It's only showing up to there.
Maybe I should see somewhere else. Uh
anyway, so let's not go and look at the
tweet. So the question you ask is has
have India and Bhutan reached some kind
of agreement or understanding?
I wouldn't know about it. I I wouldn't
know. I have no
privileged access to um confidential
information from within the government.
I don't have any of that. So I can't say
clearly Indian Bhutan have a have a
pretty good relationship. Um
and Bhutan I mean Bhutan sees India as
it as its protector right. Bhutan
essentially is an Indian protectorate.
It's a very small nation can't defend
itself from a nation like China. So it
needs Indian protection. So clearly
there is a special relationship. But has
is have the two nations reached an
agreement or understanding of merger? I
I would not know about it.
Hyphen says, "In India's GDP is nearing
$5 trillion, but but with 1.5 billion
people. How meaningful is that figure
compared with smaller economies that
have far fewer people?" It's a great
question. It's a it's a simple question
of GDP per capita. You take your GDP,
annual GDP, where let's say it's 5
trillion. You divide it by the
population, 1.5 billion people, right?
That gives you a GDP per capita of 2
something,000
USD which is poultry
poultree right
so actually we are a poor nation we are
a low-inccome nation
and if you compare it with a small
economy with far far fewer people you
will see those nations have way higher
standards of living because the GDP per
per capita may be like 10 times that of
India. What is Japan's GDP per capita?
Let's find out. A much smaller nation.
Okay, forget about Japan. Let's say
Switzerland.
What is Switzerland's population? It's
about 9 million, right? It's it's it's
peanuts compared to India. Switzerland
GDP per capita.
[laughter]
uh
nominal GDP per capita is uh $111,000.
So Switzerland's GDP per capita is about
50 times that of India. 50 times roughly
roughly give or take. That tells you
that the quality of life in Switzerland
is way higher. Obviously Switzerland is
a very expensive country. Go there and
you'll find out. Everything is super
super expensive but they can afford it
right. So GDP per capita is the real
indicator or measure
of what kind of living standards a
country will have. Obviously, it's not
the only thing that contributes to
living standards. If your country has a
high GDP per capita, but it's super
corrupt, you're going to still have all
kinds of problems. But overall, it's a
good indicator of your quality of life
and living standards. Jin Kumar says,
"How to keep gut healthy? Eat lots of
vegetables, eat lots of fiber, eat
probiotic things like yogurt, curd, all
of that. uh eat fermented stuff like
sauerkraut or kimchi or just eat a good
clean healthy Indian diet. Your get gut
will remain healthy.
Fast snail says why did the EU free
trade agreement take decades? Do EU
nations get to override the EU trade
agreements? Does India need to deal with
each country separately or not needed?
India doesn't need anymore to deal with
each country separately. India is going
to have India is going to deal with the
EU as a block of 27 nations. No need for
separate
dealings with each individual country.
Uh do EU nations get to override the EU
trade agreements? I don't think they can
override the EU trade agreements. Why
did the EU FDA take decades? Because the
EU was not that interested in in doing
this at the in the beginning. So this
deal is has been at least 20 years
probably more than that in the making
and the negotiations were stop start
negotiations and the EU most likely
wasn't that interested in FD with India.
20 years ago India's GDP was like way
way lower than what it is today. Right?
10 years ago India's GDP was half of
what it is today
and 10 years before that it would have
been another half of that. So maybe uh
what was India's GDP in um
2006?
India GDP
in 2006 what was it
in US dollars man? USD
okay it was less than a trillion
and what was EU GDP in 2006?
EU's GDP in 2006 was 12 trillion. India
was not even 1 trillion. So they didn't
care at the time, right? It was not that
important. But now what's happened is
that Trump has come in the way and he's
bullying everybody and he's
disrespecting the EU and he's making
life miserable for them and for India.
So now it makes sense for us to have a
FDA beneficial for both sides. India is
a much bigger economy now. Right? So
that's how it it goes. You know if you
are less important people don't care.
Vinit says
India was so chad and based from 70 to
75 punching above its weight risk-taking
based RNW information bureau in Indra
Gandhi poor but with blade like Iran
after 1990 graph gone so down
appeasement coalition
so after the '90s you had all these
coalition governments governments that
would last three months and go three
months and go three months and go you I
don't know what kind of prime ministers
let me try and remember the names of the
prime ministers You had a gentleman
called Mr. Chandra Shakhar. You had a
gentleman called Mr. HD Deviodora. You
had a u a gentleman called Mr. Aik
Gujaral, Indra Kubar Gujaral. Uh then
you had coalition governments that came
and went. The Waj governments came and
went a couple of times. Then you had Mr.
P Noimar Rahu's government lasted five
years and yeah in the '90s India was a
very different country, right? Wasn't
it? You also had the VPC government that
brought in reservations and Mundal
commission things and all that and made
a huge mess and left a mess that we are
still dealing with. So the '90s was this
very turbulent time. The USSR had
collapsed. India's big daddy was gone.
India did not have great leadership at
the time.
Um I'm sure I've missed some prime
minister prime ministers but that's
okay. I'm sure. Um so it was a period of
chaos and uncertainty and instability in
India. Poor leadership I would say no
disrespect meant or intended to the to
the the gentleman I named. I'm just
saying overall if you have instability
if you have uh if you don't have
political continuity if you have
governments that come in 3 months and go
obviously the leadership is going to be
poor because there's no time for a
leader to make any kind of uh
contribution. Um so that's how it was.
That's how it was. And then yeah, you
had yeah appeasement and coalitions and
Mundal commission and the introduction
of of of of uh reservations, the further
consolidation of divisions in society,
artificial divisions, all of that. Yeah.
Baser Bandit says, "One suggestion you
can consider using the 60-cond intro
from Geost Strategy episodes here in
live streams. those 60 seconds with that
specific music is one of the coolest
things on YouTube.
Okay, how about I consider bringing
Geost Strategy back itself perhaps? Let
me think about that. Then I could use it
for that. Maybe I can create a new intro
for this one. Have been created. Let's
see. Anyway, thank you for the
suggestion.
Shatabish says, "Our R&D to GDP poor for
years. Why low contribution from private
sector even with naturally guaranteed
high ROI when government's spending
government's actually spending decently
in comparison? Uh
yeah the private sector obviously see
there are there are issues all around
there are issues in the government there
are issues with the bureaucracy you have
the private sector okay I mean take the
example of Barat Forge by Baba Kalyani
okay they manufacture some of the best
artillery in the world barat Forge
Barat Forge okay they manufacture some
of the best artillery pieces in the
country and all kinds of other
But they don't get orders from the
government of India. So who's
responsible for that? So you have
examples like Barat Forge that do good
work but they don't get orders.
And then you have other private sector
companies that maybe are not interested
in um in R&D. So yeah, I mean
R&D is something that takes time. You
have to invest a lot of money into it.
That's what the Americans do. They
invest billions of I mean American
private companies like Google like
Alphabet Microsoft etc. They invest
billions and billions of dollars. Look
at OpenAI. They have invested how much
money into R&D. That's why they are able
to be world leaders, market leaders in
with the cutting edge technologies. In
India,
the I I suppose the older entrepreneurs
are simply not interested in that. They
just want to have an easy way of making
money. One of the easiest ways of making
money all the way from the 80s 90s
onwards was labor arbitrage. So we have
a this big pool of software developers
in India.
America has fortune 500 companies.
In the US, if you have if you're a
software developer, you can charge maybe
$100 an hour hypothetically. But in
India, if if I am a company who's who's
employing software engineers, I can pay
a software engineer 10,000 rupees a
month.
That's peanuts. 10,000 rupees a month is
what? It's it's a $100.
I'm charging 100 and and and a US
software engineer will charge a $100 per
hour from uh from the Fortune 500
companies. So I will bill every hour at
$20,
okay, to the American company and pay
$100 a month to my to each individual. I
mean imagine the amount of money I can
make through labor arbitrage. So you
have these easy ways of making money.
then why invest in why do R&D and all
who cares
that's the kind of mindset Indians the
Indian private sector has had for a very
long time right so there have been these
issues in India that's why we are where
we are Rahul Lak says what are the odds
of micro black hole in the solar system
well depends on the size of the micro
black hole right depends on the size not
not the size the mass
um there a different [snorts]
how large, how massive could a micro
black hole be?
We don't know. I mean, if micro black
holes were produced in the very early
universe, okay, um 13.8 billion years
ago
and if they have been because black
holes evaporate, right? They lose mass.
So if they have been evapor evaporating
then
so if if some of them still survive then
they would be like lunar mass sized the
size of the moon mass of the moon
roughly that's a pretty massive mass
uh no if their original initial mass
would have been lunar size and that's
why we would be able they would still be
uh evaporating today
but they would be dying out today.
So um the odds of a micro black hole
maybe planet 9 whatever they call it
maybe it's a micro black hole of some
kind maybe it's a black hole hanging out
in the fringes outer fringe of the solar
system and uh maybe that's what where we
are able to not we are not able to find
it but we are able to see that the
orbits of the outer solar system bodies
are all perturbed and out of uh you know
out of they are no longer in the plane
of the solar system. Maybe there's
something out there. Maybe the planet 9
the what we think is a planet planet may
actually be a micro black hole. Maybe a
small black hole. Maybe moon size moon
mass black hole. What's the
schwartzfield radius of a moon mass
black hole? Maybe maybe this much this
much with the mass of the moon. Yeah,
that's a possibility. So it's possible
but it's highly unlikely. Highly
unlikely. I mean and if you're talking
about real micro black holes then they
would have radiuses smaller than the
atomic radius like if it's a plank size
plank mast a plank mass micro black hole
it's it's its size would be less its
size would be less than the
uh distance between the between the
nucleus and the electrons of of a
hydrogen atom.
Okay, Abishek Singh says, "Your viewer
since 5.3 years. Thank you for
everything. Thank you so much for being
a viewer for 5 5.3 years. It really
means a lot. It's been a pretty
interesting journey." But it's I'm still
doing this because of people like you.
So I really really appreciate it. I'm
I'm very thankful to Obishek Singh, you
and all the other viewers. Thank you so
much everyone.
Nin Johan says, "Administration just did
a Pearl Harbor on General Cast. No
matter which government it seems general
cast is for paying taxes and getting
abuses, systematic subversion to erase
our identity. People this time are in
pain.
What can I say? Like I have said many
times before, India is the world's most
hindophobic country. It's a hindophobic
apathide state.
U if you're a Hindu you have more rights
outside of India than inside India in
most countries in the west you have more
rights you have more equality and one of
the things people face in India is this
this artificial segregation of so-called
casts and
the the permanent categorization of
certain casts so-called casts as
permanent oppressors and certain casts
are then categorized as permanent
victims and everyone's in the race to
the bottom everyone wants to be a
backward backward cast or backward class
or backward this or schedule this or
schedule that a rotten system and our
politicians are making it worse
horrible what can I say they claim these
politicians of yours who who you vote
for that they don't believe in cast
you talk to them they'll say that one of
the biggest problems in India is cast so
if it's a problem why don't you
annihilate cast make India a castless
society remove every mention of cast
from every every official document.
Make cast irrelevant. If you want to
give reservations because otherwise you
won't you will not get votes. Then give
reservations based on each family's
economic status, economic condition,
financial condition. Those who are below
the poverty line or near the poverty
line, give them reservations.
Maybe for 10 years, for 20 years, but
not permanent, right? This politician,
these are the solutions, simple
solutions to the country's problems.
These actually can be implemented. But
your politicians they don't want to do
this. They want to keep dividing the
country. All the politicians that's the
problem.
Honey Sharma says I don't want to jinx
it but yesterday how India flattened New
Zealand I think no way we are not
willing the 2020 World Cup in February
that to India. What do I think? I
haven't really followed this New Zealand
series or whatever came before. Uh so
I'm not sure. Uh yesterday there was a
match right and Ishan Kishan hit a
century in I 42 balls. I I hear and he
was not in the team for a long time. A
guy of his caliber is kept out for non-
cricketing reasons.
Um strange even even Shami Mohammed
Shami why is he not in the team? He's
one of the best bowlers in the world.
He's not in the team for what reason? I
don't understand. Anyway, that that's a
different story. Um so India flattened
New Zealand yesterday. Did India bowl
very well? I think Bumbra was taken all
over the place. That's what I saw from
the figures. So Bumrah doesn't seem to
be in good form for whatever reason. But
uh the lefty what's his name? Arshib he
got five. So yeah I do I I do look at
the scorecards and all. I don't watch
this stuff a lot these days. Um so and
Suri Kumar also is getting runs now. Is
he good for him? Anyway I hope I hope we
win the World Cup. When the world cup
happens if we are progressing to higher
stages I certainly will watch the
matches. Uh maybe the quarterfinals and
do we have quarterfinals? Maybe the
knockout matches and the semi-finals and
final I'll watch if we are playing.
Let's see. I hope we win. Of course.
Pratam Sunni says, "How to develop
critical thinking in any daily habits?"
How to develop critical thinking? First
start by asking questions about
everything. Let's say uh so and so
minister makes a statement. Ask yourself
is this true?
Find out how to do some learn how to
fact check that. So the first see I
can't give you a long answer here about
how to do critical thinking. But I'll
tell you this at the basis of critical
thinking is asking questions.
Being skeptical. How do you how can
somebody be skeptical? By asking
questions. By doing factchecking.
Somebody says something. Don't just
believe it. Ask yourself is this true?
In what circumstances could it be false?
How can I find out? And that's that's
sort of thing that leads to this habit
of and and this the skill of critical
thinking.
MK says what's your view on MM Kiraavani
the music composer of Bahubali and RR is
he a musician or a music music music
engineer like Rahman I not very familiar
with his work I
I think I watched some of RR I don't
remember the music from that
Bahubali one I haven't seen Bahubali 2 I
did watch the music was all right I
suppose but apart from these two movies
I'm not aware of Mr. Kiraani's work. So
I could not possibly comment.
Um yeah I'm not sure. Yeah Raman not a
fan of him. Um Kirwavani I'm I'm not
sure. Not sure.
Krishant Baloy says in the budget
government of India has said that they
will start promoting Tibetan Buddhism in
the northeastern states. You think it's
to combat conversion and in the long
long term make the majority again revert
to Buddhism?
I heard that there's going to be a
Buddhist circuit in the northeast of
India including Manipur and Assam and
whatnot. Uh there has never been
Buddhism in Manipur.
Never. There's never been Buddhis
The indigenous polytheistic culture of
Manipur is called Sana Mahisam in
English.
And for the past several centuries, the
primary culture has been
mixture of version of Hinduism and and
what they call salamism right that
there's never been Buddhism in Manipur
the other northeastern states I'm not
sure but I kind of get it
kind of get it if the government
promotes Hinduism it becomes a a
communal government but if you promote
Buddhism then you are being secular
right so I see the issue in in what we
call the northeast the far east of India
is this industrial scale conversion of
people that's happened there by American
missionaries helped by various Indian
governments
So if you want people to come back to
indigenous culture maybe you can do it
through Buddhism perhaps
Tibetan Buddhism any form of Buddhi
Buddhism I suppose it's fine. So maybe
that is the intention and if if so I'll
say okay I'm not sure what what Buddhism
has to do with Manipur. I'm not sure
about that but okay at least it's not
some some other foreign religion I
suppose.
Okay. So Bishak Singh says what's the
history of Vishnovism and Abhira Gopas
tribe of India? Are they related to
modern A Yadas and Ahir people of North
India? What's the origin of both? I have
no idea. The Abhira Gopas tribe of India
tribe. See we don't have tribes in
India. First of all please use please
use um non incorrect terminology. I'm
not scolding you or criticizing you. I'm
saying let's understand what a tribe is.
Okay. What is a tribe? A tribe is a
small group of isolated people who live
in some isolated region. Maybe you're on
a hill, maybe in a forest. That's a
tribe. Typically maybe 100 people, maybe
500 people, maybe thousand people.
That's a tribe. It's a small group of
people who live in isolation from the
rest of humanity and who are pretty
primitive. That's a tribe.
In India, we don't have tribes. Rigidic
tribes. You idiots. The Rigidic tribes,
the Rigidic people gave rise to the
greatest civilization we know. They were
not they were not tribes. They were
clans.
So these you could say these are
clans possibly. I don't know who the
abas and goas are. I have not studied
their history. So I don't really know
whether they are related to the yadavah.
I I don't know. I don't know. Okay. I
don't know their origins. I have not
studied their history. What's the
history of Vishnuism?
Uh it's this it's the worship of Lord
Vishnu. Lord Vishnu is one of the three
major gods in what we call Hinduism in
English.
Brahma, Vishnu and Shiva, right?
The trinity and the trinity are
essentially the same god but different
facets of the same god. Brahma, Vishnu
and Shiva.
Um, so Vishnu, the worship of Lord
Vishnu is Vishnuism and typically you do
it in the form of the worship of the
avatars of Lord Vishnu mainly Shri Ram
and Sri Krishna. That's Vishnuism. It's
very ancient. Uh that's what what I can
say. Pascal Bandit says, "Question from
Star-Lord 32 3721. From a geopolitical
perspective, how did the 1966 rupee
devaluation affect India's monetary
influence in the region in the role of
the rupee in neighboring economies like
INR and Gulf? See the Indian rupee was
used as the primary currency in the Gulf
region. You had the Trucial Gulf
States." Okay. The trcial states,
trillial.
[snorts]
Okay. The group of seven shikdoms in the
Persian Gulf that entered into
protective treaties between with Britain
between 1820 and 1892. Abu Dhabi, Dubai,
Sharah, Ajan, Umar Aluain, Rasal Khima
and Fujira. They are now the UAE. Okay.
They became the UAE in 1971. So the true
shell states okay they used the Indian
rupee until the 19 yeah until around
1960 something u
INR the Indian rupee the Indian rupee
was the de facto currency of the crucial
states until 1959
um and India introduced the Gulf rupee
in 1959 which circulated until 1966 and
the devaluation of the Indian rupee in
1966 led to the introduction of the
dirham eventually in the UAE Right. So
that obviously was a blow to India's u
to to India's standing in India's
influence
in the region economic influence in the
region the 1966 rupee devaluation it
certainly was uh a blow to India's
influence in the region imagine if that
had not happened then even today the
Indian the RBI's Gulf rupee would would
be the primary currency in the UAE in
the in the in the in the Gulf region.
that would give India so much influence
over these nations in so many different
ways. So many different ways. It's like
we we have this habit of of digging our
own you know not of our own grave as
such. We don't dig in India's grave but
shooting ourselves in the foot.
Shaswat aims says I am in first year
MBBS. I really want to practice in India
but seeing many people glorifying
leaving India due to its toxic world
work culture puts me in dilemma.
You're in the first year of MBBS and you
want to practice in India. You want to
be a doctor in India. [clears throat]
Um people glorifying leaving India due
to toxic work culture.
Uh look when you if you're a doctor in
an American hospital, you're going to
work insane hours.
Okay. I suppose doctors if you're a
trauma doctor somewhere, you're going to
work insane hours. Um it depends.
If you have your own practice in India,
for example, let's say you get your MBBS
degree and you start a practice in
India. If you have the capital, the cash
to to acquire your equipment and start
your own practice, acquire a clinic
and and start your own practice and
you're able to get good customers after
a while, then you're going to have a
very good time. If you're working in a
hospital, you may have to work with all
kinds of other seniors and all that. the
seniority culture in in that case you
may have to face toxic culture so it
depends on what your objectives are do
you want to be in a hospital you want to
work in a hospital that's a different
environment you want to have your own
own practice as a GP or whatever as a
specialist or something perhaps that's a
different thing altogether
how much money do you want to be able to
make are you okay with the money that a
GP makes or a doctor working in a
hospital makes um or do you want to make
lots of money? It depends on so many
things. So figure out exactly. I'm sure
you'll figure it out but if not you've
not told me so I can't answer for you.
Uh I would say go wherever you're able
to achieve what you want to achieve.
Okay. If it's outside of India, go for
go for that. Um and if you will be able
to achieve whatever you want within
India, well stay in India. All right. of
the west
died with priojin says how good is or
was Russia USSR in STEM R&D and
education. Russia had a excellent
u
excellent education in the scientific
fields.
Russia did fall behind in in certain uh
technological fields such as computing
for example uh going from the 60s7s '
80s onwards but the education system in
Russia was outstanding in the USSR it
was outstanding you know the USSR
produced some of the best physicists
um in the 20th century it produced the
USSR was leading the space race until uh
1969 9 and even after 1969 they did some
things that the Americans have never
been able to do like land on Venus and
send back images and rec audio
recordings from Venus. The Americans
have never achieved that. So overall the
Russian the Soviet education system was
outstanding when it comes to science and
technology. Outstanding.
And I'm sure it's pretty good today
also.
Nakshra Agarwal says, "What makes the
F22 Raptor the most lethal fighter jet?"
Ah, the F225
Raptor, the most lethal.
Well, I'm not entirely sure about what
makes it the most lethal one, but I know
that it's the best one. I haven't
studied the details of exactly what
makes it the best. See, I'll tell you
one way of externally validating whether
it's the best fighter plane or not.
There are two u fifth generation fighter
planes. The Americans have F-22, F-35.
The Americans export the F-35 export
versions to various nations. They are
even offering it to India. Obviously,
we'll not take it thankfully.
The Israelis get the best version. The
others get various other export
versions. But the full version, it's
available only to the US, maybe to
Israel, the F-35. So, the Americans are
willing to export certain versions of
F-35s to other countries, allied
countries, basal states. But the F-22,
they don't even export it to Israel.
They export it to nobody whatsoever
because it is that advanced. It is the
crown jewel that they have. That itself
tells you that it's the best fighter
plane they have. What the details are
you can look it up but u I haven't done
that.
Meet but says what do you think of the
idea that one must achieve power at all
cost? Anything that is demanded to
achieve it is worth sacrificing power at
all cost.
Well, if you are someone who seeks
power.
So this is not for everybody obviously.
It's only for those who are engaged in
politics or or yeah politics essentially
power or or in in geopolitics. So if
you're a nation,
you should acquire as much power as
possible at all cost. Now that depends
on your value system.
Or there are certain things that some
people want to but other people will do
that. So it it depends on your on your
value system. If your value system is
such that you will it allows you to do
essentially anything at all like Epstein
file stuff okay to acquire power well
then go for it. It's your choice I
suppose. Not not for me but for you.
Sure. So what do I think of it? I think
that power has nothing to do with
morality. Power is immoral. Uh some
people want to acquire power because
they are ambitious and they they they
are greedy for power. They lust after
power. Some people want to acquire power
because they want to do something good
for the world. Depends.
Power it's like it's like money. It's
it's it's like it's like a force.
It it is not intrinsically good or bad.
How you use power is what makes you good
or bad. Um
so that's that's about power. Now
whether you will whether you want to
achieve power at all cost by doing
anything that's entirely up to you. It's
a subjective matter.
Driosin says why you call old thumbnails
cringe? Why change old haircut? People
change. Everything changes. Old
thumbnails are very basic. I had made
them myself. I did not even know how to
use Photoshop. So that's why they were
kind of cringe.
Okay.
McLevin says, "Are we a vasal?" That's
the only explanation for UGC. No, we're
not a vasal. We are not a vasal of
anybody. The explanation for UGC is that
our politicians,
they they they want to keep the nation
divided. Our politicians are for what
reason? I don't know. Maybe they are
mentally colonized and they actually
believe what the British have taught us,
which would be so sad, but it is what it
is.
The explanation for UGC is that
politicians believe whoever the
politicians are, I think you can
understand. They believe that only by
keeping the Indian public divided can
they get votes.
That's the explanation. It's not vas
minimalist Maverick says Putin told
India Russia indigenous swift will
happen back in 2025 for Russia India
trade. What's the status of that? your
opinion on building on bringing raw
agents to politics.
Um I'm not sure if Putin said that but
India and the BRIRC nations are working
on bypassing the swift system right now.
That start that process started in in in
mid 2025
and that's one of the reasons why the
Americans have Americans have imposed
such massive tariffs on India. India is
leading the way in this. How far have we
gone ahead with this? How operational is
that? I'm not really sure.
But yes, so India is is working with the
BRICS nations on [snorts] creating an
complete alternative to the Swift system
which will completely bypass the Swift
system which will make all these nations
essentially immune to the Swift PO Swift
related
sanctions that you know sanctions can
that can be implemented using Swift.
So yeah it's it's we are working on
that. Um now my opinion on bringing row
agents to politics ah
what's the point of that row agents have
a very specific set of skills
those should be used for spycraft for
tradecraftraft not for politics
and of course former row agents can can
become whatever they want they can
become podcasters YouTubers politicians
whatever
okay Sumit says
Sumit says
Why few know real Max Ooler who made his
amnesia?
Why few know real Max star Oler who made
his amnesia? I have absolutely no idea
what you're saying sir. Sorry.
Uh Posh died with Posh says allegedly
Zoran Mandan's father sir very naughty.
Um
I I suppose you understood what I was
saying there. [laughter]
Allegedly, I suppose
Vya Shashank says, "Is time a physical
reality or just a human concept to track
our growth and aging? Why do our bodies
experience a one-way flow if uh if
physics says otherwise?" Physics doesn't
say otherwise.
I mean, if you look at the equations of
physics, they are kind of time
irreversible. Sure. Or time reversible.
If you look at the Newton Newtonian
equations of motion, well, you can t put
a negative t in there and you'll you can
go backward in time. It has nothing. It
doesn't prevent that from happening. And
various other equations also you can
have reversible time I suppose. So the
equations, it's not physics that's
saying otherwise it's our equations that
we have the the equations of physics
that we have
those are our approximations of how the
universe works. That is what we have
seen of the universe. Maybe our
understanding is faulty and incomplete.
Right? These equations are not the gift
of the gods. The equations are what we
have deduced from whatever we see.
The equations are our creation.
Our equations have flaws. We know that.
We know that Einstein's field equations
have flaws. We know that. We know that
Newton the Newton Newtonian equations
also have flaws because they make
certain assumptions.
So it's not like physics says otherwise.
It's it it's actually that our equations
seem to say that time is is reversible
at least mathematically. But mathematics
in the real world you see you can't have
a onetoone correspondence in that way.
Mathematics
it encodes certain laws but there are
things in the universe that
we are not able to encode in the
mathematic equations. Uh and so the
question is is time a physical reality
or just a human concept to track growth
and aging. Time does clearly pass.
We perceive the passage of time. We know
that there used to be something called
the past. Actually, there's only the
present, but we have memories of what
happened previously.
And the the forward arrow of time seems
to possibly be a consequence of um
of the of of thermodynamics.
You know the fact that entropy of the
entropy of a system either stays the
same or increases that could be the
reason possibly for the forward error of
time. Another reason why time may may be
an emergent property of the universe may
be because of quantum entanglement. We
have very vague understanding of all of
this stuff. Time is a very poorly
understood concept. Uh we the two best
theories that we have of the universe.
One is a theory of the very large large
scale universe which is general
relativity. In general relativity, time
is a fundamental component of the
universe. It's one of the four
dimensions of the universe. It's one of
the elements of the space-time fabric,
right? So, it's in a it's intrinsically
part of the universe in general
relativity,
but it's a dimension. It's not something
emergent or something, right? Um when it
comes to the other best theory we have,
which is quantum mechanics, which is the
theory of the very small, time is not
something that emerges from the
equations of quantum mechanics or the
laws of quantum mechanics. Time is an
external parameter. It's a classical
parameter. So, none of these theories
actually gives you an answer as to what
time is, but maybe it's quantum
entanglement, maybe it's entropy. We're
not quite sure yet.
Uh, hyphen says, "Is aging an evolved
feature rather than a flaw?"
Well, there are some some creatures,
some organisms that don't don't age,
right? There are some organisms that
don't age at all.
So, maybe it's it's an evolved feature.
Maybe it's evolved. Is it is it a flaw?
I don't think it's a flaw. It's a
feature. It's not a bug. It's it's a
feature. Aging is a feature
because some organisms don't age. They
can essentially live forever as long as
nothing catastrophic or disastrous
happens to them. Which are the some
aquatic creature was it? Uh which
organisms
don't age?
Okay. Immortal jellyfish.
Uh hydra which constantly renews its
cells. Immortal jellyfish. Hydra
plenerian flatworms. Lobsters also have
tomeores that repairs DNA allowing them
to continually produce new cells and
potentially leave for an extremely long
time. Sponges, corals, sea anemmones,
tardigrades.
So you see all these all these rather
primitive or or simply simp simple
creatures some of them have this this
feature in which they don't age at all
but the more evolved organisms all have
the feature of aging. So it's more of a
feature and less of a bug. Why is it so?
Well that's that's something we have to
think about but yeah it's a feature not
a bug.
Hit dia says India's surveillance uses
Chinese hik vision etc. And cyber
security uses is Israeli exmosad run
cyber arc checkpoint software etc. Are
we doomed? We are potentially doomed. We
we use things that others manufacture
for our most critical vital
work. It's a yeah it's it's a massive
massive security flaw. See
there is one element of sovereignty that
is called technological sovereignty and
in that domain India is not sovereign.
India is not a technological sovereign
nation. The good news is that there is
no technological sovereign nation in the
world. All nations depend to some extent
or the other on technology produced by
other nations. But India is severely
compromised when it comes to
technological sovereignty. and and it's
it's scary actually [clears throat]
scary it gives uh
so much leverage to other nations
I mean imagine surveillance security
using Chinese equipment imagine that
Arun Arun thank you very much thank you
very much indeed
an DVU says followup getting government
out of the way of education allowing
non-government approved curriculum
religious schooling homeschooling etc.
Not overthrowing the government. Okay.
So, okay, let's say you allow religious
schooling.
Now, how will that help a child's career
is the question? Because at the end of
the day, the education system should
give you the skills that are applicable
in the real world and will give you a
good career. Let's say you want to be a
software engineer. Let's say you you
want to be an aeronautical engineer.
Let's say you want to be a rocket
scientist. Let's say you want to be be
be something else.
Will your religious schooling give you
the skills you need for that? No. Right.
U homeschooling can do that.
If you have a non-government approved
curriculum
and if you have let's say you know an
institution that that has a
non-government approved curriculum, it
issues a degree but that degree is not
accepted by the companies where you will
apply then you have wasted essentially
your childhood. Right? So these are the
issues the system is geared in a certain
direction
right.
So for these things to become viable
the private sector even even the public
sector will have to be in a position
where it accepts certificates from
nongover approved uh educational
institutions or don't need certificates
at all only look for skills. So that
evolution needs to happen. Then we'll be
able to get the government out of the
way of education even if they don't want
to.
Ryik P says would we see a major
military buildup from all countries in
the near future as the US starts flexing
its muscle and are we all heading
towards a big war? Well, I hope we are
not heading towards a big war. We may be
heading for instability. We may be
heading for more regime change
operations like potentially America
hitting Iran possibly, right? That sort
of thing may happen. I don't think we
are heading for a big war right now
thankfully. Yeah, we don't see signs of
that. We could see a localized war
between the US and Iran. Maybe India
Pakistan also could happen. Taiwan seems
to be unlikely unless the Chinese go
crazy. So that's the situation. Now will
we see a major military build up from
all countries? No. Only some countries
have the resources to have a proper
military buildup. India is one of those.
The Pakistanis will also do that with
American help. Russia is already
obviously building up. China is also
building up. The US will build up. So
the major countries, France also, the
the EU will do that. The NATO nations
will do that. So we're going to see more
build up militarily. But not all
countries. Most countries don't have the
resources and they can't afford to do
that. No African nation will do that.
None of the various nations in Southeast
Asia can afford to do that or need to do
that even if they may so desire and so
on. So only some nations will do it.
Abha Patartel says is there any role of
foreign occupation on Britain in English
language monkeyness
English language monkeyness?
Okay. Uh is there any role of foreign
occupation on Britain in the way the
English language has evolved? Of course.
Of course. See, the original population
of the British islands
was the people who constructed
Stonehenge and those monuments,
those Neolithic monuments.
Those people
were wiped out.
Some of their DNA survives. Their their
female DNA survives. Their male DNA was
wiped out, which means their males were
massacred, but the females were
continued to were allowed to continue to
exist. Who massacred the males? A bunch
of invaders from far away east. The
Yamna they invaded England the British
islands and they were killed off the
males. That's why the male DNA
disappears but the female lineages
continue which means that they took the
women forcibly and procreated with them
and that's how the original
that's how a new population was created
in the British islands. These people
became the Celtic peoples eventually.
But even the Celtic people, oh yeah, the
Celtic peoples. Yeah. They say that
their ancestors came from far east,
right? The children of Danu.
Danu, the Vic goddess Danu.
So those are the Celtic people. Then you
have an invasion by the Romans, Julius
Caesar, etc. So they invade the British
islands and subjugate the people there,
the Celtic peoples, and rule over them
for like four centuries roughly.
So the Romans leave behind some DNA.
Obviously naturally that's going to
happen among in the population. Then the
Romans Roman Empire you know it it
slowly collapses. The Romans withdraw
from the British islands and after that
the angles and the Saxons and and the
Judes invade. These are Germanic
invaders who come and subjugate the
Celtic people and the they become the
dominant elite the rulers um and they
come in large numbers. So now you have a
Celtic population and a Germanic
population, Anglo-Saxon population.
Eventually they intermingle over time.
The north remains more Celtic. The south
becomes more Anglo-Saxon. Right? North
is in Scotland, Ireland. That's more
Celtic even today.
Then you have [clears throat] the Viking
age a couple of hundred years where the
Vikings took over England from time to
time, right? The great heathen army and
so on and so forth. So you have Nordic
DNA that comes in which is also kind of
related to Germanic DNA which is why in
the north of England in Durham in
Yorkshire you have more Nordic DNA in
Scotland you have Celtic plus Nordic DNA
in Ireland you have more Celtic and less
Nordic DNA and very little Anglo-Saxon
Saxon DNA and so on. That's how all this
happens. Then in the year 1066 AD you
have the Norman invasion. The Normans
were half French half half Nordic but
they spoke French and then you have new
DNA that comes in and with each DNA
comes new languages and stuff and that's
how eventually you come up with this
thing called the English language which
is an amalgam which which which has a
basis a bedrock of of German grammar and
German structure with a lot of French
vocabulary and vocabulary taken from
many other languages. That's how this
happened.
Karthik Ayar says, "YouTube is not
allowing me to criticize Donald J.
Trump." Well, shall I do that on your
behalf? I understand YouTube has all
kinds of fantastic
censorships and restrictions and all.
What's What's my subscriber count right
now? Let me check my subscriber count.
Let me see. My subscriber count right
now is 951 something. Oh, wow. They
allowed me to go above 950. For the
longest time, they had stuck me on 949
like for like 8 9 months. Now, it's gone
above. So YouTube has all these issues.
My channel has been very badly affected
by YouTube. We know that. So YouTube is
not allowing you to criticize Donald J.
Trump. Well, let me criticize him for
you. He clearly has been exposed as a as
a pedophile, as a pervert, as the kind
of person you don't want to be in the
same room with. Yeah, I totally agree.
The details in the Epstein files are
disturbing. They're disturbing. They are
disgusting.
Horrible. Disgusting.
And I've not even had the
courage to watch any of the videos. I
don't think I'll watch any of them.
Apparently, some videos also are also
there in the Epstein files.
So, what it tells you is that these
people who rule the US are a bunch of
monsters.
Monsters.
Only monsters will derive pleasure from
from harming helpless people. And the
most helpless members of society are
children. And these people eat children
apparently and kill and torture children
and do all kinds of god knows what kind
of horrific things. These people rule
the US and they preach they preach
human rights
and democracy to the world. Absolute
hypocrites.
Innocent USA. [laughter]
Innocent uses Arab
Chava channel Journey Poker face good
quality content to joyful clearly even
more good quality content. How was
journey? Journey has been good. I'm not
sure exactly what you're saying but uh
the journey has been good.
Um it's been good. I've enjoyed it and
it continues. Okay. Thank you.
Okay. uh hyphen says were colonial
empires primarily motivated by economic
imperatives or by elite power
consolidation through violence.
I don't know about elite. I don't know
what what you mean by elite. Whoever is
powerful eventually becomes elite,
right? If you're powerful, you can
control money and that's how that's what
that's what makes you elite. So
initially you have somebody who comes
and grabs power and then they eventually
are called the elite. um colonial
empires
were they motivated by colonial empires
are empires of occupation and
extraction. Okay, the one we are
familiar with is the British Empire. Uh
they occupied India for they ruled India
for about 2 and a half centuries, right?
The presence of the Anglo starts in
India around 1600 AD 1600 or 1610
whenever it was. They they set up this
factory in western India in Surat right
and then eventually you have the slow
gradual expansion of their influence and
eventually in the 19th century beginning
of the 19th century they defeat the
Marata Empire in the two Anglo Marata
wars that's where they start ruling the
country properly
um they they were motivated by by
plunder
okay the reason they set up the Indian
administrative system and all this stuff
was to plunder India more effective ly
it was not to make you know make India a
better place and to uplift India and to
bring their civilized ways of life into
India. They did the exact opposite. They
they u they engineered hundreds of
artificial famines starved hundreds of
millions of Indians to death did did
worse things than the epsteel fines
we'll talk talk about to Indians. Okay.
But they did all of this in order to
plunder India as effectively as
possible. and they took out maybe 70 or
something trillion dollars worth of
today's money out of India in terms of
value. So they were motivated by
economic imperatives. They were
motivated by plunder by loot and they
were willing to do whatever it takes
whatever it took to plunder the country.
Jior TV says did the Shunga dynasty try
to erase traces of the Moran Empire on
purpose because of hatred? Because of
hatred I am not aware of the Shunga
dynasty trying to erase traces of the
Moria Empire. I'm not aware of that at
all. Um, did that happen? I am not sure.
I have not read about Shunga efforts to
erase traces of the Moria Empire. I
mean, look at Pushya Mudra, right? Look
at his life and his career. Pushy Mitra
Shunga was the Sapati, the
commanderin-chief
of the last Mori Empire. Brihadit Da I
think his name was. And the last morian
emperor was incompetent and India was in
deep trouble because of him. It was
being overrun by yawanas and whatn not
kind of milletchas right the economy was
bad and empire was crumbling. So
pushaunga did the right thing during a
military parade he assassinated the
morian emperor the last one and he
installed himself on the throne. Now
after that what happens? Pusha Mitra
rules for the rest of his life and then
his son becomes the next emperor. But
Pushya Mitraunga never called himself
emperor. He always called himself
synapathi.
So he so he if you call himself yourself
synapati you are acknowledging the fact
that you were theapati to the previous
morian emperor right? So it doesn't
indicate any desire or any attempt to
erase the trace of the Moran empire. So
at least pushing did not do that. I
don't know about his descendants. His
descendants did not last long, right?
They did not continue the empire for too
long.
Aayush Gupta says which is the best
startup you liked in India and also
Russian girls are mentioned a lot in
Epstein file. Can't Russia take any
illegal action?
I'm not sure which startup I have liked
in India. I think all startups are good
as long as they succeed and and make
India a better place, more prosperous
place. I will refrain from naming any
one startup. Uh Russian girls are
mentioned a lot in Epstein files. Can't
Russia take any illegal action? Where
where does Russia go? Is there a court
that that that rules over Russia and US
both? What legal action can Russia take?
Where which court does they go to? Do
they go to the Russian Supreme Court,
the American Supreme Court, some other
international court of justice which the
Americans don't recognize? Where does
Russia go? Think about it logically.
There's no place for legal action. What?
You go to the UN, the UN is anyway
useless, right? There's nothing the
Russians can do.
Uh Brown Leprechaun says, why does Trump
47 look more hurried than Trump 45?
Because he has been given a mission by
the US establishment to achieve a
certain certain number of things. He
also knows that he's got three years
left in his term and after that he
doesn't get any more time as the
president of the US and he is driven by
public by by personal ambition. He wants
to be remembered as the greatest
president of all time. So that's why he
wants to achieve as much as as much as
possible in the next 3 years. That's why
he looks so much more hurried.
Gora TV says do you see India getting
rid of secularism and democracy in the
future? Someday it will happen but it
doesn't look like it'll happen soon. The
current lot of politicians and leaders
they worship democracy in secularism.
They worship the constitution.
Right? So I I don't see that happening
anytime soon.
But yeah, India will only regain its
civilizational status once we get rid of
at least secularism and this this
current system
this Westminster
parliamentary democratic system that we
have. We need to this is holding India
down.
It's like it's like a 100 kilo weight
put around your throat. Terrible.
Griik P says which is wiser to pursue in
life power or money it depends on on who
you are and what your objectives are if
you're a politician you should pursue
power money will automatically come to
you if you're an ordinary person what
power will you get if you're an ordinary
person who is not into the pursuit of u
you know political
if you're not into politics then you
should try and accumulate money because
money will give you the freedom that you
seek in Restore
Barat says, "Torn between multiple
citizenship and OCI for global freedom,
money and power as an outsider or Indian
citizenship with full rights to improve
governance but less freedom. Is this
path viable in India?" Okay. What are
the options? You have multiple
citizenship and OCI for global freedom.
So let's say you are a citizen of two
nations and you also have an OCI card.
So that gives you global freedom um
money and power as an outsider.
or Indian citizenship with full rights
to improve governance but but less
freedom. Is this path viable in India?
Which path?
The [snorts] path of Indian citizenship
with full rights to improve governance
but less freedom. It's a viable path but
it's for you to decide whether it's for
you or not.
[snorts] If you have decided to dedicate
your life to improve governance in India
and to improve the lot of India, then
you can pursue that path only if you are
really wealthy
and an Indian citizen. You can also do
it as an OCI card holder. If you are a
very wealthy person by investing in the
right sectors in India,
yeah, maybe setting up businesses in
India, setting up local with with local
whatever the method is,
you can do that.
But if you so there are multiple
options. If you are a wealthy person
with with a foreign passport, you can
still and an OCA card, you can still do
a lot to help things in India. You can
set up foundations. You can you can have
people mentored who will provide the
right kind of leadership to India. There
are people who do that from outside of
India. You know, some of them are
actually foreign agents, Trojan horses.
Maybe you can be an actual non- Trojan
agent, you know, somebody who does good
for India. So, it's entirely up to you
what you seek to achieve and how wealthy
you are. You can only make a big impact,
positive impact if you are wealthy.
So if you have wealth and if you have an
OCI card then you don't have to become
an Indian citizen
you get almost the same rights apart
from voting rights if you have an OCI
card and you can do a lot to help India
with an OCI card and wealth so
that's what I can tell you sir all the
best I'm glad that there are people from
who of Indian origin who seek to uh
serve India in some way so all the best
sir do well I wish to the greatest of
success.
Pravin says, "Apologies for the typo in
my previous India Bhutan super chat. The
tweet of Ashi Vashnov is on 18th
September 2025. Just my observation."
Okay. Should we try and look for that
again? Ashwini Vashnov tweet. Um,
give me a second.
Um, let's go to
All right. Give me a second. Let me
search for this.
Ashwini Vishnav.
Um,
[clears throat]
Ashwini Vishnav. Okay, let's find his
Twitter and let's just search for
Bhutan. That may be a better way of
doing things. Search for Bhutan.
September 18, 2025.
Okay.
I'm not sure about that. Let's go back.
Um,
okay. So, I think that will take time to
search for it, but okay. Anyway, so
thanks for letting me know. I will check
it out at a later at a later stage.
Maybe after after this live stream,
we'll check it out. Thank you. Uh R.
Raun Rajger says, "I mean no Epstein
mail leaks 911 month skipped." You mean
September 11 to that thing? There's been
nothing about that in the Epstein uh
piles.
That's interesting. Okay. Interesting.
Mr. Sid says, "How do planes or jets
descend? Do they dip the nose or adjust
the flaps for descent? I'm curious about
the science of descent and landing." You
know aircraft they have wings right? The
wings they have flaps and spoilers.
There are these things these these uh
surfaces that you can control you know
uh which can rise like that in the front
of the wing and in the back of the wing.
In the back of the wing it typically go
typically if the wing is like this the
the surface at the back which is called
the flap will go down. This is called
the flap or the or the spoiler. And
there's a surface in the front also
which which can be raised or whatever.
And by doing that you can slow the speed
of the plane
and you can also pitch the nose down. I
mean even in the tail of the plane you
have the the these two little smaller
wings that can pitch the tail up or down
by which you can also make the nose go
up or down. And through all these
control surfaces you can actually
essentially uh control every aspect of
the plane's movement.
You can, you know, if you have two
wings, you can put one of the flaps up,
one of the flaps down. By that, you can,
you can change the angle at which the
plane is. So, when you're making a turn,
you typically want the plane to to go at
an angle like that, you know, so that
inside the plane, people are not thrown
around or whatever. So, you can do that
by by pitching one wing wing down, one
wing up and going in that direction. You
can even do interesting things like side
slips
by using the horizontal stabilizers
control surfaces and so on. So you've
got multiple control surfaces in fighter
planes. You even have cannards at the
front of the near the nose of the plane
and so on. So each aircraft based
depending on the design has a bunch of
control surfaces and by using those you
you can control the rate at which you
descend and whether you stay uh going
stay at a certain altitude or start
descending or even go up and also the
engine output matters right. So if you
want to descend you typically uh bring
the output of the engines down so that
the plane also slows down and you can
descend. If you want to if you want to
ascend, if you want to make take the
plane upwards, then you typically
throttle up the jets and you go faster.
That's what you do.
Ritikani says, "With the US squeezing
global oil outlets, China may end up
relying more on Russia for energy."
Correct. Would that shift give Russia
more leverage and power over China,
which they were losing? Absolutely.
So, what the US is doing is it's trying
to do that. It's trying to squeeze
China. There's only a certain number of
sources of oil and gas in the world,
right? Sources of energy that China so
desperately seeks. China doesn't have
sufficient oil and gas reserves for its
needs. It has to import a lot of oil and
gas. Mostly oil we're talking about. And
there's only a few nations where you
have oil. One is Saudi Arabia, one is
Kuwait, one is Iran, one is Iraq. uh you
have the UAE, you have uh Nigeria, you
have Indonesia and so on so forth and
Russia and Venezuela. Venezuela gone, if
Iran is gone, Iraq is controlled by the
US, Saudi is controlled by the US to to
a large extent. Um um UAE on the side of
the US and so on. So if the Americans
get to control all the sources of oil
for China, then they have to completely
rely on Russia, which gives Russia
tremendous leverage over China. But it
also isolates China which is good for
the US and then if the US can cut a deal
with Russia which will not that be be
easy at all but so the objective is to
isolate Russia and China and bring them
together and then perhaps deal with them
individually or something.
D with precision says many are labeling
Epstein as KGB honey trap. What's my
opinion?
I don't see Epstein. I don't I don't
believe that for one second. Yeah. Blame
everything on Russia. US is clean
always, right? Russia did all this bad.
KG Ipstein was a KGB agent. What utter
nonsense. He was pure American. This is
American culture. It's not Russian
culture. This is the American culture.
This is this is American values and
western values and western culture.
That's what we seeing.
Han Sharma says, "Is it important to go
to gym gym if I want to be jacked? As of
now, because of cat, I can't really go
to the gym." Continue. You think
push-ups and pull-ups will be enough or
what else can I do to achieve a decent
aesthetic physique at home?
You can acquire a couple of kettle bells
and a couple of reasonably strong
dumbbells, reasonably heavy dumbbells,
what you can handle and do push-ups and
pull-ups and crunches and sprints.
And if you Yeah, that can give you a
decent uh aesthetic physique if with the
right diet for sure. You can use the
kettle bells and dumbbells for other you
know core workouts and uh shoulders and
traps and arms and back and whatnot you
know kettle kettle bell I mean in a gym
you get all the various weights you know
a whole range of weights you can't do
that at home but if you get the right
weights and it's it's usually good
enough so if you can't go to gym if
you're stuck at home then I think a
couple of kettle bells a couple of
dumbbells is enough along with push-ups
and pull-ups and crunches and sprints or
walks or whatever that is enough to give
you a decent um aesthetic physique at
home. Um as long as you have as you
ensure that you have a good clean diet,
right? All the best sir do well. Harish
Sharma says good night sir and I humbly
request to watch tumb. I shall watch
tumb. Thank you so much for the
recommendation and the reminder. Thank
you.
Uh, Rohan Beir says, "Your personal
favorite upper and lower body
exercises." Well, I like barbells.
Barbell bench press and barbell rows. I
love rows. I done so many rows, tens of
thousands of rows. Um, that's my
favorite upper and lower body exercises.
I like the deadlift, too. I really enjoy
it. And I do uh and I do this exercise.
I don't know what it's called. You know,
there's something called the shrug,
right? You can do shrugs with barbells
or dumbbells. I do these
I I I I do these uh
I'm not sure what to call them. I do the
shrugs, but like I do these very
rapidly. And that's not quite the right
way to do things. If you you're supposed
to, you know, shrug the weight up, bring
your shoulders to your ears and hold for
a couple of seconds and then bring it
down slowly. But I do it very rapidly,
not as a shrug, but as an exercise that
builds the forearms, the grip strength,
even the back. It's even good for the
core. So that's one of my favorite
exercises. I I where did I see it first?
I think I saw Bill Goldberg, the WWE
wrestler, do that and I incorporated
that. That worked out great for me. So
that's one exercise. I like lower body
um standard. You know the deadlift is
also a lower body exercise of course but
also the squat and the lunge. I think
squats and lunges are enough for lower
body.
Okay. So that brings me to the end to
the end of today's uh session. All the
super chats are dealt with.
So that's about it. Thank you very much
everybody for all the questions. It was
great fun as always.
And uh Manhattan asks me do I have
six-pack abs? I currently do not have
six-pack. I do have a six-pack, but it
is not visible right now because there
is a topping on top of it. [laughter]
I need to bring it out again. Yes, I
need to excavate the six-pack. So, yes,
that is the mission now that for me.
Okay, so thank you very much everybody.
I really enjoyed this. And there's one
more super chat. Let's deal with that.
This is the last one for today. Please
don't take any more super chats guys and
girls. Would you travel in SSJ and
SSJ00 and IL1 if they enter service? The
Sukoy Super Jet and the illusion 114 if
they enter service? Oh, I would love to.
I would love to. Yeah, I'll take the
first opportunity to travel in that. All
right, thank you everybody. Thank you so
much. Good night, good day wherever you
are in the world. And do always remember
to keep asking questions, keep learning,
keep raising your standards. And I will
see you very soon in the next live
streams. Take care. See you soon.
Bye-bye.